In the future, probably Japan.
"Robots" have long seen practical use,
and this is the era just after the common deployment of "Androids."
I'll ask again.
Yes, master.
The last time you went out was...
It was two days ago.
Reason?
Shopping for groceries and clothing goods.
It was a command from Mother.
Did you do anything besides your orders—
I did not.
That's strange.
Hey... recently, you converse with it like it's a human.
Even mom does it—
What about mom?
Just the other day, she was playing dress-up with it...
For her generation, it can't be helped.
But if you do that, it means you're already a dori-kei.
Breakfast.
Understood.
That is the so-called "house-roid", isn't it?
You may say that, but isn't that the same as not having any emotions or personality?
Even so, if the dori-kei youth...
are having feelings for these house-roids,
doesn't that mean they are bad at communicating with real life humans?
See what I mean?
Status, Sammy!
Morning duties are housecleaning.
Shopping is scheduled for the afternoon.
Time of Eve
Isn't that it?
Ah, I remember that.
It's here at last!
I have brought your change of clothes, master.
Thank you.
Huh? You thanked this thing?
I don't know, am I meant to?
No way.
Eh, she's a dori-kei?
What was that?!
I'm telling you, she said she didn't go to that café.
What about that, uh...
on your mobile phone.
The movement records?
Yeah, that.
Could it be a problem on this end?
That's why I say you trust robots too much.
Then are you saying Sammy's lying?
Sa-...?
Uh...
No...
Our android...
So that's Sammy, huh?
Well, it's not that I'm really trusting her...
Why don't you recite the three laws of robotics?
We're not in a law school...
Stop arguing and just remember it already, master.
Um... firstly,
A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.
Do not inflict harm onto humans.
That's right.
Secondly,
A robot must obey orders given to it by human beings, except where such orders would conflict with the First Law.
Obey commands from humans, unless this contravenes the first rule.
Oh, so you do remember after all.
Thirdly...
Was there a third rule?
Pffft..."Protect yourself."
A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection does not conflict with the First or Second Law.
These are the codes of conduct for a robot.
In other words, that's all there is to it.
What do you mean?
That is to say,
there's no law against lying.
First Law: Do not inflict harm on humans
Second Law: Obey human commands
Third Law: Self-preservation
No way!
It's surprising how you don't know this.
Well, this means that whatever Sammy says,
you can't trust it.
She was going to go shopping this afternoon, wasn't she?
What?
I'm talking about Sammy!
She was just shopping, she said.
There's no choice but to confirm whether that is the truth ourselves.
We're going in after all?
What is it now, don't you want to confirm it?
That's not it...
Then that's fine.
Hm! Alright.
What's with that?
I said I'm going!
Then let's go.
Ah, let's go.
Time of Eve's rule
In this shop,
there is no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time...
Ah, welcome.
Hm?
What's up?
It's too early to be relieved.
It might come in after this.
Hehe.
- Friend of Eve -
We're going to wait  here?
For the time being, shall we stick around till dinner?
But I don't really want to confront it here.
Isn't it alright here?
But I'm shortsighted.
You can't see it, even from here?
After all, I can't see anything if I take my glasses off...
Meow!
Huh?
Chie, come down from there!
I'm a cat!
Oh, I'm so sorry, lads.
It's best for kids to play around freely...
...indeed.
Ah, freely.
Ah...
Come along, give it up now.
Those round things are weird.
Chie, there's something that you want to eat, isn't there?
I am a cat!
and... ice-cream!
If you don't sit down, you won't get to eat it.
Heh, sorry about that. Once something catches her attention, she forgets about everything else.
It's a piano.
Are you going to play it?
I told you, I've quit playing.
I'll play it.
That old man's kid is a human, right?
No matter how you look at her, she's a human. But you know...
What?
...Akiko appears to be human in this place too.
Huh?
How lonely.
I will be lonely too.
Can't we meet everyday?
No, I have my job...
You are meeting other women outside, aren't you?
No, that's not it.
Please don't leave me by myself.
Yes, I know.
Ah.
Shall we go somewhere else?
What were you doing?
Socializing.
Order something already...
Two blends.
Two Evlends!
It's ice cream!
Here you go, sorry about the wait, Chie
A cat's tongue can deal with the cold.
You... are scared, aren't you?
What of?
That Sammy will come.
What are you on about?
That your own robot is at some unknown place, doing whatever it wants.
"Violating human authority!"
Is that it?
Did your dad say that?
Well, I don't understand.
I don't even have one.
Why don't you have one?
Ah, she's here.
I'm here!
I don't know why Sammy would lie.
I have more difficulty understanding robots without rings.
I'll be right back.
Huh? OK.
Rikuo!
What, what's up?
Ah, what?
You're completely different.
Heh? Really? I'm so happy!
Um... that's not it, I have a question.
Hmm...
Um... where's the ring on top of your head?
It's off. If I don't look like a human, it'll be a violation of the rule.
But robots have...
Alright, this conversation ends here.
Ah?
Ah, Chie!
I'm a cat.
Chie, what's up?
He's wearing something weird.
Something weird?
Meow, meow!
What do you want of me, Blade Runner?
Why don't you do a better job of observing me?
To have a man's intense gaze on me...
is not comfortable at all.
I'm sorry.
Violate the rules here, and you won't have fun.
No, rather, it would be meaningless to be here.
...or so I've been told.
I don't have it!
Ah, is it alright for today?
Well, please give my regards to your friend.
You'll get them back eventually, probably.
Probably?
She hid my hat before as well.
My glasses got taken.
So where was your hat?
My hat?
She hid it right?
Ah, that's right, and then I asked where it was, and Chie had it all along!
Please come again!
She had it?
She hid it inside her pants!
She must have taken a liking to it.
Sorry, something came up.
What a nice atmosphere.
What's up with Masaki?
Hm... I don't know.
Ah.
It won't open now.
What?
Once someone leaves, it's kept locked for some time.
Why?
We treasure privacy.
Um... is this size alright?
Yup.
There're larger ones.
If it's too big, the other members of the household will find out.
Alright then, hold on a second.
I'll get you a good blend.
What should we do, Rina?
I'm extremely sorry, please let us leave first.
Here, today's coffee.
Sorry for always taking your shop's merchandise.
Did they like it?
I wonder if they will like it...
You could always ask them yourself.
I can't do that!
Why?
He hates it when I do anything independently.
"Don't take it upon yourself to do this," he'd say.
It's alright.
He will definitely understand you.
Well, isn't this place's rule a local one?
You can't compare it with the Robotic Laws.
You're violating the rule again. You'll get caught.
You won't say no matter what?
I'll keep it a secret from Nagi, so this conversation ends here.
Secret?
Huh?
You really can keep secrets...
You are having quite a strange conversation.
Everyone has one or two things that they're hiding.
No, but she's a—
Ah... um...
I'm also keeping something a secret from this girl.
I'm not saying that I won't lie to her either.
But it's for this child's sake.
The secret Akiko is keeping from you...
is for Rikuo's sake too, isn't it?
Yup, yup.
"...may not inflict harm on humans."
"These are the codes of conduct for a robot."
"Did you do anything besides your orders—"
"I did not."
Because I will get hurt...
...for my sake?
To begin with,
she didn't tell you the location of your glasses because...
Haha, she just wanted to play with you, isn't that right?
They're not in her pants...?
She seems to have handed it to someone.
Huh?
Oh, it's already this late.
Are you heading back?
I have to prepare dinner.
Thanks for this.
Um..
Ah, you finally realized.
Why did you keep quiet about it?
No one asked.
So the guests and staff at this place are buddies huh.
What?
Damn!
Rikuo.
What is it, damnit!
Doing things by herself!
She's my...!
Sit down!
Yes...
This cup's on the house.
That girl... when was it that she first arrived...
She was a bit confused at first,
but she gradually warmed to us.
"Warmed to you"?
Yup. She was able to talk to us about a lot of things.
The mother who bought her clothes.
The nightmare she sees sometimes.
The guy who would not play the piano any more.
Just the other day, she came in,
saying she wanted to make good coffee.
She seemed to be troubled by a lot of things.
Troubled?
You don't understand, do you?
Whether what one is doing is right...
or wrong...
Here.
As long as you are obeying the rule,
Time of Eve is always open and welcome to you.
So in the end, I lost sight of him there.
You followed him outside?
I wanted to check if he had anything above his head.
That shop is definitely up to something—
Um.
I was thinking of going there again sometime...
Oh, I'll come with you! This time we'll totally resolve this enigma!
Ah... OK.
Alright, see you then. Say hi to Robot Sammy for me.
Question.
What is it?
Um... that shop...
Master, I am sorry...
Coffee.
Understood.
The coffee recently...
...is quite delicious, I think.
Thank you very much.
I saw a lot of interesting things.
But I haven't pinned down anything specific.
It's not related to the Ethics Committee, is it?
If it were them, they wouldn't use such a careless shadower.
I'll let it swim free for a while, see where that takes us.
Indeed.
Chairperson Ashimori,
as it is, it appears individuality is beginning to manifest.
This means the suppression circuit is...
"Assumptions distract from the truth."
That's what Shiotsuki would say.
I will continue my duties.
Preview
- Lovers of Eve -