In the future, probably Japan.
"Robots" have long seen practical use,
and this is the era just after the common deployment of "Androids."
What is this drawing of?
You can't recognise yourself?!
This... is... me?
Yes! It is a drawing of ****!
Time of Eve
Dad returns!
Sunday Lunch
Yes... yes... complainants, huh?
Got it. I'll tell him... yes, yes.
Rikuo?
Hmmm?
Why are there so many complaints?
Was that dad?
Yes.
In the past, whenever new models were released, there would be mountains of complaints.
Why?
Many users become irritated.
Because unlike today, the AI did not have fuzzy logic.
I don't get it.
Let's see... Sammy. Something to drink.
Would an after-meal green tea be satisfactory?
Yes.
Certainly.
See, it can respond appropriately, even to an ambiguous command.
In earlier days, this was not possible.
Order: Something to Drink
Rikuo (Mid-Meal) Order
What type of drink did I want, when did I want it,
Expostulate
Japanese Menu = Green Tea
Breakfast Norms = 1 Cup After
Answer: Green Tea After Meal
it would have to ask repeatedly to clarify these vague areas.
If I got irritated and rejected the questions, it would get an error and freeze.
You're talking about the old times, right?
Oh... But there have been a strange many complainants recently.
Ones that want to prohibit the use of Houseroids,
or want us to pay their collection costs in advance.
Ah.
Currently, the Ethics Committee is...
Please co-operate in reporting vagrant robots
Vagrant robots may have damaged patterns of thought...
Stuff like that.
...conducting a voluntary recall of robots which have been disconnected from their Masters' control and neglected...
That AI seems to be quite an amazing invention.
Have you heard anything about it?
Uhm, the one which is like a genius scientist?
Yes, that's the one.
The versions are being upgraded so quickly, we'd be able to buy something identical one day.
Aah, but the return costs are becoming very expensive.
Well, there seems to be a way of avoiding payment and getting away with it.
But the Houseroid at Satou's place...
That cute model...
I'm telling you I'm not interested like that!
This sucks.
Hey, are you also...
Masaki!
Huh?
Are you... interested?
No.
C'mon, don't surprise me like that!
Hey, are you free today?
Uh, I've got some things to take care of.
You seem to be always busy recently.
Where do you go?
Well how do I say it...
Somewhere noisy, I guess.
Isn't it quiet?
You mean there are no customers.
No...
Huh?
Have they come back?
This really is a strange shop, isn't it?
In various ways.
E-Excuse me!
Um... Ms. Nagi... Why do you work here?
You can just call me "Nagi".
Because I like it here.
I also like the people who come here.
So on days like today, when I can't see the faces of those guests I love,
I get lonely.
Um... we...
Huh? What?
This... can I get a refill?
Oh.
I'll just bring out the beans. Please wait a while.
Enjoy your stay.
It really is quiet, isn't it?
Time of Eve's rule
In this shop,
there is no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time...
It's the LUH model.
Huh?
It's the Houseroid model which came out around the time we were in primary school!
It's still around huh...
I've never seen it before.
It was not very popular back then.
There were many complaints that it was hard to use.
It seems to be shaking pretty badly, though...
- Doll of Eve -
Do you have some business here? We are just customers.
Do you understand what a "customer" is?
I am also a "customer".
Huh?
Ah.
Hey!
I am Masaki. This guy is Rikuo.
So, who are you?
W-What are you talking about?
Normally, humans introduce themselves.
Huh?
Introduction is...
a process wherein I communicate my name, is it not?
This guy is trying to imitate humans.
Heh, it's abiding by the rule.
Yes! It is a drawing of ****!
I am called... ****.
Why did you cover your ears?
If I do not communicate my name,
the introduction process cannot be concluded.
In other words, I will be unable to verify my status as a human.
My name is ****.
I-It's alright! You don't have to overdo it.
Overdo what?
The introduction!
Why is that? Just now, Mr. Masaki...
Normally, humans introduce themselves.
...is what you said.
Masaki! This one cannot deal with fuzzy interactions!
What should we do?!
Anyway, if we don't let introduce itself...
What about that sound?!
For the time being, we'll have to bear it.
We're sorry! Go ahead and say it!
Like I said... I am ****.
I-It's a nice name huh...
I also think so.
It's a very important name.
That's wonderful.
Whoa!!
Where might the restroom be?
But that broken part...
It's been left alone until it became like that.
It should be returned to the maker for repairs-
You're talking about those things again.
But, one would expect, in this day and age-
Rikuo-kun.
He is a guest.
You already understand that, don't you?
Everyone who comes here is the same.
Excuse me.
Welcome. What would you like to order?
Something seems wrong.
It might not be able to decide.
This is something new afterall.
Whoa!
Ouch!
Order! This, one more cup of this!
I would like to order what Mr. Rikuo is having.
Yep, two Evlends!
Going to drink the coffee?
I might be pushing it with three cups...
No, I meant the robot.
Huh?
That mouth is just a speaker.
What if it tries to imitate humans and drinks?
If it does that...
Hey, wait up! The third law prohibits robot suicide!
The Three Laws of Robotics
Third Law
A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection
does not conflict with the First or Second Law.
Does this guy not understand that drinking could be dangerous?
That is true. It couldn't possibly... be drinking... right?
Whoa!
Is something the matter?
Coffee is...
...dangerous!
What... What are you doing?
What...?
Thanks for waiting on the Evlend!
Why?!
It's for the customer to drink, isn't it?
Don't say such weird things.
Ah!
Hey, hold it, wait!
Cut the switch!
I haven't done this before!
O-Order! Just order it to do it!
Oh, I see!
Drop the cup! It's an order!
Why?
"Why"?
That lady...
It's for the customer to drink, isn't it?
Don't say such weird things.
...was what she said.
I am a customer.
Ah! Question!
What is it?
Um...
H-H-How old are you?
In terms of age? This year I will be eight years old.
What?
He probably means that he was manufactured eight years ago.
You thought I was a bit big to be an eight-year-old human, didn't you?
No, not really-
No, Mr. Masaki, it was written all over your face.
Why are you only concerned about this sort of detail?
But I am eight years...
Eight years...
Eight...
Hey!
There is a conflict between logic and the rule. It cannot answer!
What should we do?!
Whoa!
Well! There are many types of eight year olds!
Other eight-year-old humans who look like me
are in existence, is that right?
That's right!
I do not have data about that.
Please explain in detail.
What?
T-T-T-There's a frequent visitor to this store!
You mean there is someone who comes to this store, who is eight years old?
What is their name?
She... She's called Chie! Well, she's...
8 Years
Eight years old... not quite that.
Not quite eight years
That's right! She's big! Like, her voice is...
The most important thing is that it's believable.
What is your job?
I helped with childcare.
Ehh... Childcare huh?
Yes. At that place with the parents and their only son.
Hey! Help me out here!
What?
It's tough does this by myself... you know...
I am a customer.
Thanks for the drink.
Water tank.
What was all that hard work for?
The danger has passed... maybe...
Excuse me. Where might Nagi be?
While I was looking after her during her nap,
I fell asleep myself.
Something weird is sitting there!
It's not good to say such things.
Chie, let's go back?
I'm a cat!
Umm...
Excuse me.
She's called Chie...
Is Chie the one who is not quite eight years old?
What?
Whoa!
This person! This is Chie!
What? What are you saying?
I'm a cat!
This person is...
This one here is a cat!
No, that's just her favourite line-
Can't we just call her a cat?!
She said it herself, so let's leave it at that!
Yes!
I. Am. A. Cat!
Right! I will escort you to the exit!
Good-bye!
Presently, the data is very complicated...
Hey! Are you alright...?
The weird thing fell.
Um... is there any way I can help-
I'm begging you, please, just go!
How is it? Can it be fixed?
This is already-
Thank you, Rikuo-kun. But...
Since we're here, let's have a good chat.
Hmm, so, you've always been working at that house?
Yes. That was my place of work.
I was tasked with looking after the son, but,
now, he has grown to a stage where I'm no longer needed.
That job, did you like it?
Yes.
The son bestowed a name upon me,
and even now, I remember it well.
It's an important name.
That child's name! What was his name?
The son was...
**** was his name...
What about that family's surname?
Their address... contact details?
You...
As I thought...
I'm grateful that you asked about my name.
Everyone who comes here is the same.
You... called me...
...didn't you?
What?
...name... don't... forget it...
Yes! It is a drawing of Katoran!
Is it broken?
It was illegally abandoned...
What?
When a new one is bought, the old one should be returned to the maker.
At that time...
The collection fee...
Because they didn't want to pay it, they deleted their personal information...
This child, you see, wanted someone to remember it.
Its own name...
That's why it has been evading the Ethics Committee.
It probably didn't know...
It probably didn't even know it's own name.
That was probably erased as well...
That's just like a robot, isn't it?
Even having lost something ages ago, it did not realize it.
It remained in this child's heart the whole time.
The time when it received its name, those precious memories...
Heart? What do you mean heart?
Masaki...
You often said so yourself, didn't you?
"Because it doesn't have a heart, it doesn't understand music."
How long are you going to stay there blubbering?
Stop it already!
What? Isn't it strange?
Huh?
You too...?
Vagrant Robot Report Form
So they're also carrying out disposals of vagrant robots.
The Ethics Committee.
That doesn't mean I was doing it.
She's really ignoring us huh...
Isn't that normal?
Sammy is like that at home too.
Why is it only different at that café?
Affection is not something they hold.
Preview
- Melody of Eve -