Where's dad?
He went to the Family Court.
He is expected home shortly.
There's no way mom did anything wrong.
That's true.
But you can't just blame dad.
Because neither side is completely wrong.
But...
I have a favor to ask you.
Sure!
Let's not tell dad about this conversation.
Why?
Because it would hurt dad.
You don't want that to happen, right?
So, that is the favor I ask of you.
Sure!
Masakazu, there's a problem.
Seems it's broken.
Good morning, Tex.
Tex...
Hey, Tex!
Tex!
Time of Eve
In the future, probably Japan.
"Robots" have long seen practical use,
and this is the era just after the common deployment of "Androids."
Next, the report from the preliminary investigation.
This shows the places that
seem to be inciting excessive human-robot interactions.
There's too many.
1408 places.
We gathered all possible information
and codified all of it.
Groundless rumors and urban legends included.
We need to narrow it down.
Unfortunately, not all these places clearly violate robot law.
It's a grey zone.
And the fact that there are so many of places
shows the limitations to robot law as it stands now.
But, these places must be eliminated.
We'll do a cursory investigation of all the places,
and then pick targets for full investigation.
After that, hand them over to the media.
But it's impossible given the sheer number!
That's true, in terms of manpower...
For the first time ever,
we'll use androids for the cursory investigation.
We've already secured a large number–
We're getting them ready now.
What happened to your allergy to robots?
Fight poison with poison.
I suggest you think of it like that.
Continue.
We'll only fully investigate the places
substantiated by the android investigations.
And, we'll record all androids and humans seen at the places
and do follow-up investigations.
We'll immediately report suspects
to committee members who are in the police force
and urge them to make arrests.
What's happening with the Android Promotion Committee?
Someone has sniffed out the preliminary investigation.
Their relationship with the APC is unclear.
Also, lobbying has been quieting down.
So, don't forget that some parties
will try using this investigation to trip us up.
We will order the android investigators
to keep their ties with our committee absolutely secret.
Memories of that incident are fading.
We must not make the same mistake again.
Go on.
Media strategy division.
CIO Masaki will make a TV appearance–
My wife records them all.
Drives me nuts!
I'd like to emphasize
that our Ethics Committee is raising the alarm about
robots infiltrating into daily life, that's all.
Woah! What a lady killer!
Huh? How?
Hey, you changed the channel!
Thanks for letting me stop by!
Children treat robots like people
no matter how primitive the robots are.
And that impedes the relationships
that we're supposed to have between humans.
One Evlend!
...it's an encroachment on human dignity.
Sure.
The issue I'm raising here is–
Hey, why doesn't Masaki come anymore?
Actually, a lot has happened...
Like what?!
Well, the biggest reason is...
This guy is on TV a lot these days, huh?
Yeah. Like the old days...
What's this?
The Robot Ethics Committee has been around
since androids started being used in households.
More than 10 years.
I've heard that at it started out
as a radical anti-robot organization.
I had no idea.
'Cause they've been quiet for the last few years.
What do you mean?
Their radicalness led to an injury.
The Tokisaka Incident, right?
I've heard of it.
...it's also referred to as an accident.
At any rate, they were severely censured
and the head resigned.
Since then,
they've been quiet, at least until recently.
You've lost me...
Does it have anything to do with Masaki?
...that is our stance.
Thank you very much, Mr. Masaki.
Today's guest for Zoom-in Scramble has been
Atsuro Masaki, Chief Information Officer of the Ethics Committee.
Masaki...
That's right... his family circumstances...
I invited him today too–
So Masaki is his last name.
You're hung up on that...?
Not that!
- Friendship of Eve -
So, how's it going?
There's this café called Time of Eve,
Rikuo's a big fan.
I go there too, so who am I to talk.
Humans and androids talk to each other!
It's totally absurd.
Yeah?
Say something.
I'm coming in.
Who're you talking to?
My mobile phone.
I hung up already.
You had it make coffee?
Yeah.
You're at home a lot these days.
Did something happen?
Tell me everything.
There's nothing.
Oh, I see.
Don't trust robots too much
when it comes to things you eat and drink.
THX, tonight we'll write up the minutes from today's meeting.
The data is in my terminal.
Tell Masaki he's welcome anytime.
Sure, I'll tell him.
But don't get your hopes up.
See you.
Come again!
Um, he's gone...
You know, I don't think Rikuo minds anymore.
That's the impression I get.
Nagi, you don't understand Rikuo.
I've known him longer.
I'm sure he doesn't want to see me here yet.
Really?
Hey, who cares about Rikuo?
Of course we care about Rikuo!
Oh... really?!
Don't go telling Rikuo strange things.
Masaki's not going to report this place, is he...?
Meow.
If that happens, this café will have to close.
But it's such a wonderful place.
Sammy,
do you remember how you first came here?
I thought you invited me.
I'm not able to bring anyone here.
You probably learned about Time of Eve
from someone who'd been here.
And Sammy, you brought Rikuo and Masaki.
So if Masaki brings someone from the Ethics Committee,
there's nothing you can do about it.
That's the end of these connections.
And the end of this café.
Nagi, that's OK with you?
In this café, everyone's hearts come together as one.
I just want to see it through...
...how big can this circle grow?
Um, Master–
W-What?
Do you want Mr. Masaki to visit again...?
...to the Time of Eve...
Yes, I'd like him to come again.
Me too.
OK, I'll definitely bring him tomorrow!
Masaki!
Today–
I'm not going.
She said she wants you to come again.
Don't just say things.
It's true!
Who?
Nagi, and–
Sammy said so too!
And that guy said he wants you to come too.
They want me to come?
So what? It's a houseroid!
Right.
That's right.
You've changed.
Masaki, what's going on?
You're just like I was, back then.
You'll feel love, only to be betrayed later.
It'd be better if that café didn't exist.
That's it. It'd be better if it didn't exist.
Dad! I want to talk to you about something!
The THX is gone.
Masakazu, did you give it an order?
No...
It just went off...
It's completely broken.
Gotta find it right away, and get rid of it.
Get rid of it?
Of course!
It's dealt with lots of Ethics Committee material.
Gotta take care of it, before it becomes a headache!
Masaki, I'm at Time of Eve. Can you help me?
What's that sound?
An ancient robot—an elderly customer—is here.
It says to close the café!
I said, what is that sound?
The screen...
Anyway, it won't stop, whatever we say!
And this THX model won't talk.
Hey—what did you just say?
This café is the gray zone, right?
Do something with that robot law of yours...
That was fast!
Close this establishment immediately.
Tex, stop it.
T-Tex?
What are you doing here?
Oh, so that's what this is about?
You bring someone's robot,
and you want to make a scene, huh?
I don't know how you brought it here,
but you guys got Rikuo's robot to come here.
You can do all kinds of things.
This is a strange place, after all.
Nagi didn't bring it here.
Akiko...
You'll go that far to get me to come here.
I'll tell you my story.
It brought me up, long ago.
It was my best friend.
Then one day, it suddenly stopped talking.
I was a kid, and thought it was family.
I felt hurt and betrayed.
That's it. No big deal.
There must be a reason why it didn't talk.
I agree.
It doesn't look so broken down.
I know.
I was 4 or 5 years old,
but I could guess what was going on.
My dad ordered it to stop talking.
Told it not to talk, no matter what happens.
He tried to drive us apart.
Just like something like my dad would do.
Orders from parents get priority.
Masaki, you're very perceptive.
What's perceptive mean?
I didn't know that when I was a kid.
I kept trying to talk with it.
I begged forgiveness, in tears!
If commanded, it can ignore a crying, wailing child.
For years.
In the end–
They can't understand people's hearts!
Use androids in the cursory investigation.
This café called Time of Eve... I go there too...
Record all androids and humans... urge arrests.
...should be eliminated.
I am going to b-break t-this café's rule.
You are in violation of robot law 9, article 3.
According to data in my possession, you are an android.
If an android turns off its ring while in motion,
it is in violation of robot law.
What's going on?
Why is Tex speaking?
What about dad's command?
A command...
It's breaking a command.
Breaking the Second Law...
...can only be for the First Law...
The First Law means... danger?
A human here is in danger...?
But... who does Tex know to be human?
Only me.
I'm in danger?
Tex is speaking...
to protect me?
So,
it is necessary to take legal action
against your owner.
I require information on your owner.
We order the android investigators to keep their ties with our committee absolutely secret.
Masaki!
I'm not letting go!
I'm not letting go
until you talk to me.
Tell me!
What were you thinking?
For so many years.
All that time.
Watching me, all those years.
You were right there with me.
Tex, help me!
Speak to me!
I couldn't speak to you...
I always wanted to be at your side...
I...
...always...
Masakazu...
It wanted to protect you.
I know that much.
It won't speak, once the danger has passed.
It's still bound by dad's command.
You wanted me to understand too, huh?
But, after all, I can't accept this.
It might be impossible now,
but someday it will talk, for sure.
Don't just say things.
You're wrong.
It's not like I don't have a reason.
But I can't express it well.
I've seen so many things here.
There's a lot of problems.
Each time, it's distressing.
But I feel like this is the right path.
It's the same for you, Masaki.
I'm sure...
You might be right.
I'll tell dad that I brought you out of the house.
I... always... Masakazu...
Let's go home.
How did it get in?
I held it.
I lifted it up.
You really are demanding a lot!
Someday I'll get you to say thanks for today.
I love everyone.
I'm so happy we can all be here.
They're going home together!
Hush!
Should I have helped them?
No, it's enough that you watched over them.
It might have turned into another dangerous incident.
I'm sure Shiotsuki understands that much.
Indeed, Time of Eve's is rule #1138.
But he's not necessarily involved.
An article about the Tokisaka Incident, from when it happened?
No... this is...
It's the real article, before the contents were replaced.
It says the victim was...
...a minor... a little girl.
Time of Eve – pending
I forgot your Evlend today.
I thought something was missing.
How did Tex get to the café?
You don't know?
You know?
I thought you were a regular here.
Rikuo, you've got a long way to go.
Still a long way?
Huh? Someone new?
I'm going to say hello.
This is my tale of the Time of Eve.
Welcome!
Take a seat!
I'll go take your order.
Lots more happened to me, but...
You might not be here for long, but enjoy yourself!
...that's another story.
I'm so tired.
You really helped me today.
It was my pleasure.
Hey, come over for a sec.
What is it?
Bow your head.
Like this...
It looks good on you.
Thank you... very much.