In the future, probably Japan.
"Robots" have long seen practical use,
and this is the era just after the common deployment of "Androids."
Protected witness has left the room. Arriving shortly.
Time of Eve
No matter how similar they look, they are still different from humans of flesh and blood.
So, in the case of androids which are used for sexual purposes...
Sexaroids are just urban legends!
This is just going to make the declining birth rates even worse.
Love doesn't lie there.
Ethics Committee
Hasn't this commercial been appearing more and more recently?
Ah.
Status, Rikuo.
At 12:03 PM, he left the house.
It appears he will be having lunch out.
I'm the one just saying it, but
you come here really often when you are free, don't you?
Hm... Skipping classes?
Compensatory holiday.
This isn't something a shop assistant should say.
Sorry. Aside from Rikuo-kun, I thought Masaki-kun was a bit of a delinquent.
He's a scholarship student, surprisingly.
Don't say anything unnecessary!
It's not something to hide anyway.
Hey, if you're looking for someone to talk to, there are other people.
Do you always carry that with you?
Yeah, I use it to shoot various things.
Well, we'll get around to it eventually.
Thanks for the meal.
You're welcome. I'll bring over your after-meal Evlend.
Evlend... Evlend...
What?
I've stopped feeling uncomfortable about it!
Ah! Not my reading glasses!
Chie, give it back!
I'm a cat!
There might be no point just sitting around.
Well, we just want to know what this café is all about,
I've got no intention of getting close to any of the robots.
We don't know about anyone other than Akiko.
What about them, to my right?
A Dori-kei getting sexual with his own android.
Oh...
No further explanation needed.
Where are you staring at?
You know...
I wasn't staring!
No, you were...
I'm saying I wasn't!
You stared.
I wasn't staring!
You were staring.
You were staring!
You two sure get along well.
Haven't heard that one before!
No way!
Just two boys getting all excited is pretty lonely you know.
The next time I catch you staring...
I wasn't staring!
At what?
So you're jealous of Koji-kun.
I'm not!
He's just very interested, right?
Hey!
Why don't you two join us here?
Time of Eve's rule
In this shop,
there is no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time...
Wouldn't it be better not to do anything unnecessary?
Was it unnecessary, really?
I think it would have been more consistent to let things develop independently.
Four people will simulate more conversation, right?
- Lovers of Eve -
He's Koji, I'm Rina.
Ah, nice to meet you.
I'm Masaki, this guy here is Rikuo.
The next time you stare, I'll smack you.
I wasn't staring!
Did you see it?
Subconsciously huh?
You two get...
You two get along well, don't you?
No way!
Haven't heard that one before!
Or have I?
Ah, you sure come here often.
Yes.
Do you two come here together?
No, separately.
It sure is going splendidly, huh?
Ah, that's the Cinema Tide?
Eh? Oh... Yeah.
Can I have a look?
Ah... Sure.
Um...
The switch is there.
Does he like it?
What?
Ah, it's beautiful.
Can you see a preview of it?
Yes, if you press that triangle over there..
It's a much-discussed model, isn't it?
Capacity's massive!
I put 500 into it.
Oh, that's right...
Because of the M-LINK, I think...
Um... Hold on...
Eh, Cine-tide sure is awesome after all!
Um... That's about it, so...
How do I turn this off?
What is this?
It's not what you think.
It's far... Your heart.
No matter how much we meet, or get close to each other,
I feel uneasy.
Finally, I understand the reason.
Please don't leave me alone.
That's quite a drama.
My fault?
It is your fault.
Sorry about the wait!
W-What is it?
What?
I'll go after her.
What's wrong?
Well, what do you call it? A scene of carnage?
Protected witness has arrived.
I was deployed as my master's guard.
Then... Koji is..?
Up till now, what have I been doing??
It seems the emergency repairs were incomplete.
To come here, was for Koji's, that is
your master's protection?
No. I took my own initiative.
That... Shouldn't it be looked at by the manufacturer?
I can't have anything to do with my legal manufacturer.
If my maker were to find out about me,
my master will be at a disadvantageous position.
Other than that, I would like to be here a little longer too.
Not even going for repairs...
In this store, the one who acts the least natural as a human
is me.
Am I right?
I would not be surprised if I were destroyed sooner rather than later.
That is why I am autonomously resisting my useless learning functions.
Koji has... Treated someone like me
in the state of a human female.
That is why I think when I am here... I am happy.
But
the woman in the photograph...
You're kind, aren't you?
But it'll be alright,
because I think Koji's kindness will not change.
Despite everything...
I'm going back.
Excuse me!
The coffee...
When the flavour of the coffee changed,
I was angry at first, but
when I came to understand various things, I was happy, if just a little.
Uh... Even though the other person isn't a human...
Tell him!
Tell him what you want to tell him, even if he's a human!
Why... Do you think that?
You know, don't you, the feelings you had at that time.
Probably.
Ah... How did I come to say such things...
Huh?
So you're serious about this one?
Something's been bothering me since just now.
There is not a single picture of you with Rina.
But I guess you couldn't have that.
It would be bad if people knew you had a make-believe lover.
No... If this one was a robot too...
She's not a robot!
Then all the more so...
What are you doing here?
She's not my make-believe lover!
Then are you saying this relationship is for real?
"There is love,"
that's not what you're trying to say, right?
You want to say this:
"For a human, a human partner is the best."
So you do understand that.
I understand.
I know that.
As you have said, Rina and I cannot transcend the relationship between a human and an android.
I think there are things we cannot understand about each other.
There's no way you could understand each other.
You see, I
want to help my master.
Huh?
My master is very similar to Rina.
I want to help my master.
Yesterday, too, I saw a lot of people.
I don't care about that.
But, master...
Master, you should look for a new partner.
A human one...
That's enough. I'm tired.
You're enough.
I'm going to become a robot.
So stay with me always.
My master is morbidly dependent on me.
But I don't know what to do about that.
When I first met Rina, I thought this person was the same as my master.
The way she behaves and touches me,
and the fleeting expressions she sometimes shows me...
I want to know more about Rina, to better understand my master.
I want to help my master.
It's the First Law!
About all this... Can you keep it quiet from Rina?
The café's rule?
I don't want to hurt anyone.
Whatever suits you, huh?
Aren't you being a useless person?
It seems no one can really attain happiness.
Thank you.
We should get out of here.
In that case, please excuse us.
Huh?
I guess there are all sorts:
Of humans?
Androids too.
Sorry about hitting you earlier.
Huh?
I mean your eyes were accurate.
I should have taken a good look myself too.
Huh?
Masaki.
Hmm?
Have you awoken?
I'm not a junior high student just reaching my puberty!
Hm?
But, Rina is...
No, it's the other way round, right?
Wait up.
What did you say Rina was?
To come here, was for Koji's, that is
your master's protection?
No.
Oh!
She never once said her master was Koji.
Master
She didn't say it.
Outside of this store, they are unrelated?
But they both said the other is human.
Human
There's a discrepancy here.
Here you go! Thanks for waiting.
They might not have realized... About each other.
Yup. That's it for the hints.
It's the same!
Will you please explain this properly?
Partners not knowing what the other is...
It's the same for androids.
The pair of them are mutually interested in each other...
For the wrong reasons, that is.
They also have things they are hiding from each other.
So what?
It's like normal love.
You've said something good.
But, don't interfere too much.
Love between androids...
Pseudo-love, huh?
So the woman in the photo the other day...
Who was that?
A love triangle between androids.
It's a bit hard to explain.
A difficult-to-explain woman, huh?
Androids tangled in blind love...
Don't go into weird deviations!
You'll tell me about it properly someday, right?
Welcome home, master.
Nao and mum have gone out for dinner.
Sammy, please take care of the rest.
What did you put on your head?
Do you not like it?
Preview
The second part of the first season, coming in Spring!
- Doll of Eve -