В майбутньому, можливо Японському.
"Роботи" давно використовувались у практиці
і ця ера наступила одразу після впровадження "Андроідів"
Що?
Всі записи успішно скопійовані, хазяїне.
Питання...
Яке?
Ні...
Відмінити запитання...
Кави.
Прийнято.
А де... Ну, тобто...
Статус: Сім'я.
Ваш батько на роботі,
мати вийшла до моєї активації,
Пані Наока досі в ліжку.
Час її повернення?
3:18 ночі.
Ох... Як мені кепсько...
То не варто було написватись.
Спочатку мені було добре.
Замов собі кави!
Після вечірки, ця штука прийшла мене забрати.
Мені було так ніяково.
Як щодо сніданку?
Відмінити сніданок!
Вибачте, повторіть команду, будь-ласка.
Сніданок на одного негайно.
Прийнято.
Our domestic food self-sufficiency ratio will be exceeding 80% soon.
Domestic food self-sufficiency ratio exceeding 80%
Agricultural Ministry
The biggest pace of expansion since robot
labor introduced into primary industries.
This was after the investigation by the Agricultural Ministry...
Would you eat a tomato created by machines?
In such an age, treasure warmth.
Ethics Committee
Whoa! In other words, "Dori-kei" is a psychological dependence on androids, yes? Yes?
Recently, this is what android-obsessed young people have been called,
and we bring you our investigation of these "dori-kei" people.
Ah, how disgusting, aren't they like clones?
I guess the androids are skilled at various things.
Whoa, they're intense!
Isn't it lonely? Not having any friends...
You should be careful too...
What do you mean by that?
Time of Eve
...we combed it out...
Rikuo, I saw your sister yesterday.
In the middle of the night, right?
At the station, she was pretty out of it.
I told you she got home safely.
You did it?
Our android did.
That's why...
I say you trust robots too much.
It's not a matter of trust.
C'mon, what are the whatchamacallit laws?
The three laws of robotics.
First Law.
Do not inflict injury on humans, protect humans.
Oh... is that why it brought her home?
It's not like they're worried about humans.
If you have an android, you should at least think about these things.
You're one to talk, you don't even have one.
Hey... what do you think about this?
That's a lot of numbers.
These are movement records! For my android.
Is something wrong?
Are you free after this?
I want you to come with me.
Where to?
That's... I don't know.
What's up with that?
It's been acting strange recently, coming home at weird hours.
Your robot?
So I got concerned and investigated...
its movement records.
And?
Twenty hours ago... that'd be yesterday afternoon...?
It went out on its own.
That's because... it had things to do, right?
Here?
Hmmm...
You're lost
Here? Seriously?
I wonder if the GPS broke?
You wouldn't know for sure unless your robot was actually here.
Hey...!
Isn't it a bit suspicious?
If we don't go in...
It is suspicious, eh...
Then should we go home?
Time of Eve's rule
In this shop,
there is no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time...
This is...
Welcome!
Please take any free seat.
I'll take your orders soon.
Right, over there, yeah?
Yeah...
It might only be a short while, but...
enjoy yourselves, alright?
- Time of Eve -
A café?
It's a café.
Androids going to a café?
We didn't exactly come here to drink tea...
More importantly, that rule...
It's pretty dangerous.
This sits in the grey zone in robotic legality.
The appearances are hard to tell apart.
Hey! Listen to me!
He's here.
What?
Isn't that the android from just now?
Hmm?
There's no ring.
You can't be serious...
Is this still in the legal grey zone?
Have you ever seen a robot without a ring?
This is a serious breach of robot regulations... you can't distinguish them from humans.
Who the hell is he?
What would you like to order?
This... Eve Blend...
Evlend.
That's...
I'll have the same.
Two Evlends!
Obey the rule, alright?
Huh?
Ah... I just thought of something bad.
What?
This place's rule...
"No discrimination between humans and robots"?
That's why there is no ring.
You don't mean...
But, assuming that is true,
it might not be just his problem.
What do you mean?
How do you think it would be if all the other patrons also obeyed the rule?
Those kids are looking at us...
Yaaaah!
This is a dangerous place.
Could be.
This place...
What about it?
Tell your dad...
My old man has nothing to do with this!
What? Newbies? I heard about you from Nagi!
Nagi is good to talk to, but anyway, can I sit here?
So, where did you come from? Are you someone's friend?
Uh, no we just stumbled across this place...
Oh I see... but it's been a long time since we saw any newcomers!
Is that s—
It's always the same people here.
The person reading a book is Setoru, right, and on the second floor is Shimei and...
Ah! cute little Chie, and...
over there is Kou and Rina — aren't they close? — and then there's Nagi, right...
and who else...
Have you finished checking them out yet?
Ah, I'm Akiko — nice to meet you!
I'm Rikuo...
Masaki.
Rikuo and Masaki... I've remembered it!
Ah! Say, uhm...
Have you seen a female android around?
One demerit point.
You broke the rule.
Oh... sorry...
You don't have to say it like that, since he's not used to it yet.
But...
Infringing the rule troubles everyone!
Nagi...
She's really a good person who cares about this place a lot.
Doesn't it just happen to be her job?
Ah... she's at it again.
Nagi!
I guess it doesn't feel like a bad place.
Conversely I'd like to ask this...
Why did she come to a place like this?
What do you mean, "why"?
I know.
She wants to befriend the robots. She's a dori-kei.
What, you disagree?
Uhm, it's not like that...
Well. You'd get it just by listening to her.
We're going to be told off again for breaking the rule.
You're the only one listening, right?
Oh, here she comes.
I brought them back!
She says she's sorry.
No, uh... I was in the wrong too...
What're you getting all shy for?
That hat suits you.
Doesn't it? I thought so too!
So... ahem...
What is it?
Well, it's something about the world outside this café...
There are no androids at my place.
Isn't that uncommon in today's world?
You have them too, don't you, at your place?
Yep, we do. That's why I'm here.
What do you mean?
When you are here, you can talk to anyone you want, right?
So you get to know a lot of things.
Like what?
Like... the other person's feelings, maybe?
This has to do with my situation at home...
I think of both humans and androids as my family.
But no matter how similar we appear to each other, our insides are totally different.
We may look alike, but we're totally different.
So I often think like this...
"What do you think about me?"
That's why I'm here.
I want to talk about various things and understand a lot more.
Because we are family after all.
Ah, it's pouring down.
Huh? Isn't your android coming to get you?
I want to know what she's thinking about.
What do you think?
Huh?
It's about Akiko.
Ah, you're talking about yesterday.
Does someone like her count as a dori-kei?
I don't have any androids so I wouldn't know.
I have brought your umbrella, mas—
Isn't it better to use them that way?
Could she be... someone who treasures things?
Well, isn't she nice?
That's true, isn't it?
Why are you so relieved?
No... it's not like that.
Well, she certainly was cute.
Should we go again today?
I said, it's not like th—
Hmm?
Ak—
I'm very sorry for making you wait, mas—
Bag. Waterproof it. Go on by yourself.
Acknowledged.
Here is your coffee.
As I thought, it's that taste...
I bought a different kind of coffee.
Huh? I did not give that command!
I thought master would be pleased.
Why did you act independently?
Are you imitating humans too?
I am an android.
...not a human, master.
"What do you think about me?"
But no matter how similar we appear to each other,
Resembles
our insides are totally different.
Reversed?
We may look alike, but we're totally different.
Resembles
I want to understand a lot more.
Because we are family after all.
Hey, you're acting like a dori-kei.
Preview
- Friend of Eve -