In the future, probably Japan.
"Robots" have long seen practical use,
and this is the era just after the common deployment of "Androids."
Next up, the front page of Bankei Newspapers.
Android job types expand!
It's big news!
Where's Sammy?
She made that, and went out a while ago.
Huh?
Maintenance?
It's so annoying... once every month.
Where's it go?
An appliance shop?
Well...
Probably dad's place.
I'm sleepy, and don't feel like eating.
Android job types expand.
Androids used as school teachers?
Birth of android artists?
The piano.
What?
If you're gonna play at night, turn off the sound!
Even I'm losing sleep.
So it wasn't a dream...
Gone to teach voice training.
Sammy, take care of breakfast.
- Mom
Mom was heartbroken!
Says she can't let you help with the lessons.
Even if I get good, what's the use?
Hayama Junior Piano Competition
Robot gives guest performance.
Grand Prix - Rikuo Kikuhara
Time of Eve
It doesn't have any special abilities?
Special abilities in an android?
I found this on my old man's PC.
Um...
It's an android.
Made to be a human being's father.
I've heard about it-
They're not actually in use.
They want to use them in the future.
Read this.
Operational tests conducted in secret...
Sounds familiar, huh?
Not particularly.
It doesn't mean he's like that.
It's like robots are butting into everything.
After art, next it'll be love!
Masaki!
Would you eat a tomato created by machines?
Time of Eve's rule
In this shop,
there is no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time...
Welcome!
You're alone today?
It's not like we're always together.
You are!
She's alone too?
Yeah...
Shimei's got something to take care of.
- Melody of Eve -
So you do childcare too?
Chie is a customer!
Right?
Meow...
What's he up to?
Leaving Chie on her own...
I'm a cat!
Don't say things like that!
Sure, sure...
Hopefully your dad will be back soon.
He's not my dad!
Huh?
So who is he?
He's called my... fos... ter... par... ent!
I'm back, Chie!
I'm a cat!
Oh, Rikuo!
Huh? Where's Masa?
It's not like we're always together!
Sure you are!
You seem kind of out of it.
Out of it, meow.
You're wrong!
Oh-
Chie, let's read a book!
I don't feel like it...
You know which book Uncle Shimei likes?
How about I show you?
Meow!
She's good with kids.
'Cause Akiko knows how to handle herself.
Unlike me.
What does Shimei do for a living?
I'm not sure what he does either.
Except for doting on Chie.
He should have taken her with him.
Probably.
But Shimei's the one who is suffering.
I kind of understand.
'Cause I've taken care of her many times.
Many times?
Right, every month.
Cats study too!
Are you OK?
I didn't get enough sleep.
That's not what I mean.
Seems like you're in a bad mood.
What's it matter, you all hate me anyway!
What do you mean by that?
They say there's nothing in your heart at birth.
It's empty.
Cats too?
Right. But you talk with lots of people,
and feel and see lots of things,
and gradually your heart comes into being.
Cats too?
Right. But you're still a child.
You're going to experience lots more emotions.
Not just Chie.
Shimei, us, and also-
Rikuo?
The cat understands...
Really?!
Chie got scolded before...
Are you lonely without Shimei?
Do you like Shimei?
Meow.
Shimei goes off somewhere on his own.
I wonder where he goes.
...even though he gets lonely.
Rikuo!
She's just a child, you know!
Um... sorry.
Bathroom...
It's Chie's turn!
Rikuo, excuse us a sec.
Sure.
I can do it by myself.
That's my Chie!
Shimei first brought her to this café
quite a while ago.
According to that elderly gentleman,
she really likes it here.
I didn't mean to bully her.
But, something bothers me-
Anyway.
All human beings hurt their companions sometimes.
What are you getting at?
I guess that got you angry.
You're saying I'm a bad guy 'cause I'm a human?
You say some interesting things.
Do you think robots never hurt others?
What is it that hurts others?
It's not such an easy thing to figure out.
What were your thoughts at that time?
How can you avoid hurting others?
What do you need to understand?
It's easy enough to say,
but quite another thing to put into action.
Rikuo!
You saved me!
Is that so.
I've been so terrible.
So you're gonna do administrative justice.
Seems not many lawyers specialize in robot law.
But it's still tough to get into.
What about you?
This, after all?
I'm quitting.
Why?
You mean, that thing the other day?
Yeah.
Forget about that.
It can play with precision, but...
it just stole a bit of the limelight.
It was really... good.
I was moved... I think.
By this?
Huh?
It's lousy.
Ah. Right!
I'm sorry.
I lied when I said I could play.
But you made it to the end... right?
Really, I just picked it up by watching.
I'd just heard it so many times, that's all.
Play some more, meow!
Chie, what did you like best?
When it was all broken up!
Look at that!
Rikuo...
Thanks for this.
That's not what you were playing before!
Rikuo!
Um... I'm...
The thing you used to play...
I liked it...
And Chie said she wanted to hear it.
But I've never really played it.
But she still enjoyed listening to it.
I'm sorry to have been so selfish.
I tried not to play in front of you.
And before I knew it, I'd stopped playing.
I would have hated it if even you got good at the piano.
Rikuo...
But...
To hell with all that!
I want to hear more!
Sammy might play for you!
Meow!
I'm so happy.
She hasn't been that happy for a long time.
It was no big deal...
And as for me...
I left her on her own again.
You can't take her with you?
I don't want to show it to her yet.
Shimei, could it be that you're...?
She needs me.
So I devote myself to her.
She is everything to me.
My only wish is to make her happy.
Like your performance...
That's why I was so happy.
These feelings are genuine.
I was moved by your performance, I swear.
It's OK to say that kind of thing?
Just don't tell Nagi.
Have you seen Sammy?
Come to think of it...
I think she left when I came in.
So she's gone...
For your hard work.
About Sammy...
What?
She makes a lot of friends...
It's not like I'm angry!
You were really great.
This café...
You know, I kind of like it...
Thank you.
Rikuo!
Right. I'll explain it at the next meeting.
I'm home.
Anyway, take a look at the records.
Regardless of what the upper eschelon say,
this is the best way to study them all.
Preview
- Friendship of Eve -