In the future, probably Japan.
"Robots" have long been put into practical use,
This is a time not far off after the widespread deployment of "Androids."
We've identified the information source.
As expected, it's from the same district.
This time it was transmitted via more than five other androids.
Somehow, the pattern diverged.
Just as we tho—
Trace the centroid.
Centroid identified.
I've found it on my end as well.
I'm surprised.
That is Shiotsuki's parting gift, isn't it?
What are you trying to say?
Shiotsuki's AI — code: LIFE.
Do you recall that implementation experiment?
The one the supervisor forcefully halted?
I didn't know what happened until after the experiment.
It's classified after all.
All related personnel are under protective observation.
It's all connected in ways I didn't expect.
In any case, a decision was made to protect androids of this district that knew of the café.
And it was decided among themselves.
Is this your doing as well, Shiotsuki?
Now tracing the first of the deployed units.
Time of  EVE
Logs successfully exported, master.
Question.
What is it?
No...
Cancel question.
Coffee.
Acknowledged.
Where is... I mean...
Status: family.
Your father is at work.
Your mother left before my activation.
I believe Naoko-sama is still in bed.
Return time?
3:18 A.M.
Ugh, I feel terrible.
Then you shouldn't drink so much.
It felt good at first.
Order the coffee yourself!
You know, after the drinking party, this thing came to pick me up.
I was so embarrassed.
Would you like breakfast?
Canshel breakfast...
I am very sorry. Please repeat that command.
Breakfast: one serving, immediately.
Acknowledged.
Reports indicate that our domestic food self-sufficiency rate has exceeded eighty percent.
Domestic food self-sufficiency ratio exceeding 80%
This is due to an Agricultural Ministry investigation—
Agricultural Ministry
The biggest pace of expansion since robot
labor was introduced into primary industries.
Would you eat a tomato created by machines?
In an age like this, treasure warmth.
Ethics Committee
Kaa-BOOM!
In other words, "dori-kei" comes from a mental dependence on androids, right? Right?
Recently, this is what young people
obsessed with androids have been called,
so we investigated the people who are called "dori-kei"!
Gross. It's like, "Get away from me!"
Walking arm in arm and stuff.
No way!
They're probably lonely, without any friends...
You should be careful, too.
What are you getting at?
Rikuo.
I saw your sister yesterday.
Late at night, right?
At the ticket barrier. She was pretty drunk.
I told you she got picked up.
By you?
By our android.
That's what I'm saying...
You trust robots too much.
It's not really a matter of trust.
Look, the whatchamacallit laws.
The Three Laws of Robotics.
First Law.
Do not injure humans; protect humans.
So that's why it went to pick her up, huh?
But it's not like they worry about humans.
Think about it - after all, you've got a robot.
Big words from someone who doesn't have one.
Hey, what do you make of this?
Just a bunch of numbers.
Behavior logs.
Our android's.
Which part?
Are you free after this?
I'd like you to accompany me for a bit.
Where to?
I'm... not sure.
What do you mean?
It's been acting weird, coming home at odd hours.
Your robot?
So I got concerned and investigated its behavior logs.
And then?
About twenty hours ago, so yesterday afternoon, I guess...
It made a detour, on its own.
So... it must have had something to do.
Here?
You're lost
Seriously, here?
Maybe the GPS is off?
This is no place for a robot to come.
Hey...
Time of Eve
Doesn't it seem a bit suspicious?
Gotta go in to know for sure.
I guess it is suspicious.
Should we go back, then?
Time of Eve's Rule
In this café,
there will be no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time…
This—
Welcome!
Please, take any open seat.
I'll take your orders.
Right over there, okay?
Yeah...
You might not be here for long,
but enjoy yourselves, okay?
A café?
It is a café, isn't it?
Androids going to a café?
It's not like they're coming to drink tea, right?
More importantly, that rule...
It's pretty dangerous, isn't it?
In terms of Robotics Law,
it's in the gray zone.
That rule is too vague.
Hey, listen to me!
It's here.
What?
Isn't that the android we just saw?
There's no ring.
Seriously?
Is this the grey zone?
Have you ever seen a robot without a ring?
This is a serious violation of the Robotics Law.
You can't distinguish him from a human anymore.
What is it doing?
Your order?
This... Eve Blend...?
Evlend?
That one.
The same.
Two Evlends!
Don't break the rule, okay?
Something bad just occurred to me.
What?
This café's rule...
Don't discriminate between humans and robots?
That's why there's no ring.
You don't mean...
But even if that's the case...
Aki-chan, wake up.
maybe it's not just a problem with that one.
What do you mean?
What if all the other customers are also following the rule?
Those kids... They're looking this way...
Meow!
This is a dangerous place.
Could be, yeah.
This place...
What about it?
Should you tell your dad?
My old man has nothing to do with this!
What? Newcomers?
Nagi-chan told me about you guys.
Ah, Nagi-chan is the girl at the counter!
So, can I sit here?
How'd you find this place? Are you friends of someone?
Uh, no, we just came here.
Really?
It's been a long time since we've had anyone new!
Is that s—
It's always the same people.
The person reading a book is Setoru-san.
On the second floor is Shimei-san and...
cute little Chie-chan!
And over there are Koji-kun and Rina-chan — aren't they close?
And then there's Nagi-chan, and who else?
The girl wearing the hat.
I'm Akiko, nice to meet you!
I'm Rikuo.
Masaki.
Rikuo-kun and Masaki-kun... Got it!
Say, um...
Have you seen a female android here?
One point deducted.
You broke the rule.
Sorry...
No need to put it like that.
He's not used to it yet, after all.
But...
Breaking the rule disturbs everyone.
Nagi-chan...
She's a good girl.
She really cares about this place.
That considered, she doesn't do much work.
She's sulking again.
Nagi-chan!
I guess this place doesn't seem so bad.
To the contrary, I'd like to ask this instead:
Why does she come to a place like this?
Why?
I know.
She's friendly with robots - one of those dori-kei.
What?!
You disagree?
Um, it's not like that.
Well, ask her and you'll see.
She's going to say we're breaking the rule again.
There are other ways of asking, right?
Oh, here she comes.
I got our drinks!
She says she's sorry.
I... umm... it was my fault, too!
Why are you getting all shy?
That hat suits you.
Doesn't it? I think so, too!
So...
What is it?
Well, talking about things beyond the café,
I don't have an android at home.
Isn't that uncommon nowadays?
You have them at your place, don't you?
Yep, we do.
That's why I come here.
What do you mean?
When you're here, you can talk with anyone you want, right?
So you get to know lots of things.
Like what?
Like... the other person's feelings, I guess.
This is just my opinion, but...
I think of both humans and androids as family.
But, you see, no matter how similar our appearances,
inside we're completely different.
We look similar, but we're totally different, aren't we?
So, you see, I often wonder about this:
"What do you think of me?"
That's the reason I'm here.
I want to talk with them, and understand them.
After all, we're family.
Ah, it's starting to rain.
Isn't your android coming?
She said, "I want to know what they're thinking."
What do you think?
Huh?
About Akiko-san.
Ah, you're talking about yesterday.
I wonder if someone like her should be called a dori-kei, too.
I don't have a robot, so I wouldn't know...
I have brought your umbrella, mas—
Better than treating them like that.
Maybe she's a... considerate person?
Sure, she's a nice person.
Really?
Why are you so relieved?
That's not what I mean!
Well, she certainly was cute.
Going to see her again today?
I said it's not like th—
Aki—
I'm very sorry for making you wait, mas—
Bag: waterproof it. Return home by yourself.
Acknowledged.
Here is your coffee.
As I thought, it's that taste...
I've changed the way I make it.
I didn't order that!
I thought master might be pleas—
Why are you doing things on your own?
Are you imitating humans, too?!
I am an android.
I am not a human, master.
"What do you think of me?"
No matter how similar our appearances,
Resembles
inside we're completely different.
The other way around?
We look similar, but we're totally different, aren't we?
Resembles
I want to understand them better.
After all, we're family.
Hey, you're acting like a dori-kei.
I have returned.
There it is.
I recognize it.
It's here at last!
I have brought your change of clothes, master.
Thanks.
You're thanking it?
You don't?
Of course not!
Eh, you're a dori-kei?
What's that?!
I'm telling you, she said she didn't go to that café.
Did you do anything beyond your orders?
I have not.
What about those? You know, on your cell phone.
The behavior logs?
Yeah, those.
I wonder if they're wrong.
That's what I'm saying - you trust robots too much!
Then, do you mean Sammy is lying?
Sa—
I mean... our android...
So you call that thing Sammy, huh?
Like I said, it's not that I really trust it.
Try stating the Three Laws of Robotics.
We aren't exactly in law class.
Stop complaining and remember them, master.
Um... First Law.
Do not harm humans.
First Law
Three Laws of Robotics
A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction,
allow a human being to come to harm.
Right!
Second Law.
Obey humans' orders,
Three Laws of Robotics
Second Law
A robot must obey orders given to it by human beings,
except where such orders would conflict with the First Law.
as long as they don't contradict the first law.
You do remember!
Third Law...
Was there one?
Third Law
A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection does not conflict with the First or Second Law.
Three Laws of Robotics
Protect yourself.
These are the principles of robot behavior.
That's all there is to it.
What do you mean?
So, there's no rule about not lying.
First Law
Do not inflict harm upon humans
Second Law
Obey human commands
Third Law
Self-preservation
No way!
It's surprising how people don't know this.
Well, it just means you can't trust what Sammy-chan says.
Says it's going shopping this afternoon!
W-What?
Sammy-chan is!
She said she'd just be out shopping.
Only one way to know if that's true.
We've got to go and see for ourselves, right?
Are you really going in?
What, you don't want to find out?
That's not it...
So let's go.
Yeah! All right!
What was that?
I said I'm going!
Then, let's go.
Yeah, let's go!
Welcome.
What's wrong?
It's too early to be relieved.
It might show up later.
We're going to wait here?
For now, let's stick around until dinner.
I don't want to run into her by surprise, though.
Here's good, isn't it?
I'm really short-sighted, though.
You can't see, even from here?
My distance vision is only about 0.1—
Meow.
Meow!  Meow.
Chie-chan, come on down from there.
I'm a cat!
Ah, I'm so sorry, lads.
It's best for kids to play around freely, don't you think?
Ah, well...
Freely indeed.
Come on, cut it out.
These round things are weird.
Chie-chan, there's something that you want to eat, right?
I'm a cat!
And... ice cream!
You've got to sit down if you want to eat!
Ice cream. Ice cream. Ice cream.
Sorry.
Once something catches her attention, she forgets about everything else.
It's a piano.
Gonna play it?
I told you, I've quit...
Playing, I mean.
That old man and the kid are humans, aren't they?
They sure look like humans...
But...
What?
Akiko also seemed human when she was here.
I'm lonely.
I'm lonely myself.
We can't see each other everyday?
No... I have my job, too.
You're seeing other women outside, aren't you?
No, that's not true.
Please don't leave me alone.
Yes, I know.
Shall we... sit somewhere else?
What've you been doing?
Socializing.
Order something.
Two blends.
Two Evlends!
Ice cream!
Here you go! Sorry to make you wait, Chie-chan.
A cat's tongue can handle cold things!
You're scared, aren't you?
You know a lot, don't you?
Of what?
Sammy-chan showing up.
What are you saying?
That your own robot is at an unknown place and is acting of its own accord.
"Human dignity is being violated!"
Is that it?
Is that what your dad says?
Well, as for me, I don't understand.
I don't even have one.
Why don't you have one?
Ah, she's here.
I'm here!
I just don't get why Sammy would lie.
I find it more difficult to understand robots without rings.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Rikuo-kun!
What's wrong?
Stop it!
You're completely different.
Really? I'm so happy!
U-Um...
I mean— Question.
Um... Where's the ring? The one on your head.
It's turned off.
If I didn't look the same as humans, I'd be breaking the rule.
But the Robotics Laws—
All right, this conversation is over!
Ah, Chie-chan!
I'm a cat.
What's up, Chie-chan?
He's wearing something weird.
Something weird?
Meow.  Meow.
Do you want something of me, blade runner?
Why not do a better job of observing me?
It's not very comfortable when a guy...
stares at you continuously.
I'm sorry.
You won't enjoy this place if you defy its rules.
It's lively today, isn't it?
Or rather, that would defy the point in being here.
Well, that's what I was told, anyway.
I don't have them!
Ah, is today okay?
Well then, please give my regards to your friend.
You'll get her to give them back eventually, probably.
Probably?
She hid my hat before.
My glasses were taken.
So, about your hat...
My hat?
You said she hid it.
Ah, right, right!
So, I asked where she'd hidden it, see,
but she had it all along!
Come again!
Meaning?
She had it in her panties!
She must have taken a liking to it.
Sorry, something came up.
Seems you're enjoying yourselves.
What's up with Masaki-kun?
I don't know.
It won't open right now.
Huh?
When someone leaves, it locks for a little while.
Why?!
Privacy is important.
Um...
Is this size okay?
Yes.
I have bigger ones, too.
The people at home will find it if it's too big.
All right then, give me a second.
I'll give you a good selection.
What should we do, Rina-chan?
I'm sorry. Could you please let us leave first?
Here you are. Today's portion.
Sorry for always taking things from your café.
Did he like it?
I wonder if he'll like it...
You could always ask him yourself.
I can't do that!
Why not?
He hates it when I do things of my own free will.
He'd tell me not to do it again.
It's all right.
I'm sure he'll understand.
Well, isn't it just a local rule after all?
It doesn't compare with the Robotics Laws.
You're breaking the rule again.
I'm telling!
You won't talk about it no matter what?
I'll keep it a secret from Nagi-chan,
so this conversation is over.
Secret?
So, you can keep a secret?
You two are having quite a strange conversation.
Everyone has one or two secrets.
Yes, but she's—
Time of Eve's rule
In this café,
there will be no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time...
Um...
I keep some things secret from this girl, too.
It's not like I don't lie.
But it's for her sake.
What Akiko-san is keeping secret...
is for your sake too, isn't it?
...not harm humans.
These are the principles of robot behavior.
Did you do anything beyond your orders?
I have not.
Because I would be hurt...
For my sake?
After all,
she probably didn't tell you where she'd hidden your glasses...
because she wanted you to play with her.
They're not in her panties?
She said she gave them to someone.
Oh, it's already this late.
Are you heading back?
I have to prepare dinner.
Thanks for this.
Um...
Ah, you finally realized.
Why didn't you say anything?
You didn't ask.
So the customers and staff are friendly here, huh?
Huh?
Shit!
Rikuo-kun.
What's going on!? Damn it!
Doing things on its own...
She's my—
Sit down!
Okay...
I'll give you one cup on the house.
That girl...
When did she come here the first time, I wonder...
At first she was at a loss,
but she gradually opened up to us.
Opened up?
Yup.
She started talking about lots of different things.
The mother who buys her clothes.
The nightmares she has sometimes.
The boy who's stopped playing the piano.
And then the other day, she came in,
saying she wanted to make better coffee.
She seemed troubled about a lot of things.
Troubled?
She's not sure...
Whether the things she's doing are right...
or wrong.
Here.
As long as you obey the rule,
the Time of Eve is always open to welcome you.
So in the end, I lost sight of him there.
You followed him?
I wanted to check if he had anything above his head.
That café is definitely up to something—
Hey.
I was thinking of going there again sometime.
I'll come with you!
I'll get to the bottom of this mystery!
Okay.
All right, see you then.
Say hi to robot Sammy-chan for me.
Question.
What is it?
Um...
That café...
Master, I am sorry—
Coffee.
Acknowledged.
The coffee recently...
has been good... I guess.
Thank you.
I saw a lot of interesting things.
Nothing specific yet, but...
The Ethics Committee is not involved in this, right?
If they were, they wouldn't tail me so badly, I'm sure.
I'll let it go on for a while, and see what happens.
Indeed.
Chairman Ashimori, individuality is now beginning to manifest itself.
And that means that the restraint circuit—
"Assumptions will just lead you away from the truth."
That's what Shiotsuki would say.
I'll carry on.
Love isn't present there.
Ethics Committee
This commercial's been on a lot lately, hasn't it?
Status: Rikuo.
Out of the house since 12:03.
He said he will have lunch out.
It's really none of my business,
but you sure come here a lot during the day, don't you?
Skipping classes?
Compensatory holiday.
Not the kind of thing a waitress should be saying.
Sorry.
Rikuo-kun aside,
I thought Masaki-kun was a bit of a delinquent.
He's a scholarship student. I bet that's a surprise.
You talk too much!
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Say, if you'd like someone to talk to, there are other people here.
Do you always carry that with you?
Yeah, I want to take lots of photos.
Well, eventually, I guess.
Thanks for the meal.
You're welcome.
I'll bring your after lunch Evlend.
Evlend... Evlend...
What?
It doesn't sound strange anymore!
Not my reading glasses!
Chie-chan, give them back.
I'm a cat!
It's pointless to just sit here.
I just want to know what's up with this café.
I'm not interested in getting all chummy with robots.
Akiko-san's the only one we know about.
What about those two, on the right?
A dori-kei bringing his own android with him.
No further explanation needed, huh?
What are you looking at?
Hey, you -
I wasn't looking!
You were looking.
I wasn't!
No, you looked.
You were!
I wasn't!
You were looking!
You two sure get along well.
I've never heard that before!
That's not true!
You two getting agitated by yourselves is a bit lonely, isn't it?
The next time I catch you staring—
I wasn't staring!
At what?
So you're jealous of Koji-kun.
I'm not!
He's just very interested, right?
Hey!
Why don't you join us over here?
It's dark!
It's scary.
Wouldn't it be better not to interfere?
Was that interfering?
I think it would be wise to leave things up to the individual.
Wouldn't a group of four make for livelier conversation?
This is Koji. I am Rina.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Masaki. This guy's Rikuo.
Next time you stare, I'll slap you.
I wasn't staring!
Or was I?
Subconsciously?!
You two get...
You get along well, don't you?
That's not true!
I've never heard that before!
Or have I?
Meow?
You come here often, don't you?
Yes.
Do you come here together?
No, separately.
Conversation seems to be going splendidly well.
Is that a Cinema Tide?
Yeah.
May I have a look?
Okay.
Um...
Does he like cameras?
The switch is there.
Oh, it's beautiful!
Can you see previews?
Yes, if you press that triangle over there.
It's a popular model, isn't it?
I put 500 pics into it.
Ah, right!
U-Um...
It's M-LINK, so probably...
Um... wait...
The Cinema Tide really is awesome!
Um... that's about it, so...
How do you disconnect it?
What is this?
It's not what you think.
Your heart... is far away.
No matter how often we meet or snuggle,
I feel uneasy.
I finally understand the reason.
Please don't leave me alone.
Quite a drama.
Is it my fault?
Your fault indeed.
Sorry about the wait!
Wh-What is it?
What?
I'll be right back.
What happened?
Well, what do you call it?
A bloodbath?
X has arrived.
I was deployed as my master's bodyguard.
Then... Koji-san is...
What have I been doing until now?!
It seems the emergency repairs were imperfect.
So you come here for Koji...
...for your, I mean, your master's protection?
No.
I come here on my own will.
Shouldn't that be sent back to the manufacturer for repairs?
I can't have anything to do with the official manufacturer.
If the manufacturer found out about me,
it would cause trouble for my master.
Besides, I'd like to stay here, even if just for a bit longer.
Not even going for repairs...
In this café, I'm the one who behaves least like a human.
Isn't that right?
It wouldn't be strange if I were destroyed at any moment.
That's why, I'm autonomously resisting my useless learning functions.
Koji...
treats me, in this state, as a human woman.
So I think that when I'm here... I'm happy.
But...
The woman in the photograph...
He's kind, isn't he?
But I'll be fine.
I don't think that Koji's kindness will change.
After all... I'm going back.
Wait!
The coffee!
The taste of the coffee changed.
I was angry at first...
but when I understood, it made me feel a bit happy.
Um...
Even though she isn't human...
Tell him!
Say what you want, even if he is human!
Why do you think that?
You understand the feelings you had at that time, don't you?
Probably.
I can't believe the things I'm saying.
Huh?
So this one is for real?
It's been bothering me for a while.
There isn't a single photo of you and Rina together.
Not like you'd dare take one.
It would be bad if your make-believe lover were exposed, wouldn't it?
Wait... What if this one's a robot too?
She's not a robot!
Then all the more...
What are you doing here?
She's not my make-believe lover!
So you're saving it's for real?
You're not saying... there's love here, are you?
What you want to say is,
"For humans, a human partner is best."
So you do understand.
I understand.
As you say, Rina and I can't transcend the relationship of an android and a human.
There are things we can't understand about each other.
There's no way you could understand each other.
You see, I...
just want to help my master.
My master has a lot in common with Rina.
I want to help my master.
I saw a lot of different people again yesterday.
I don't care about that.
But, master...
Master should find a new partner.
A human one—
I've had enough...
I'm tired.
Koji is best for me.
I'll become a robot.
Stay by my side forever.
Master is completely dependent on me.
But I didn't know what to do.
When I met Rina, I thought, "This person is just like my master."
The way she touches me, and the expressions she sometimes shows me...
I want to help my master by learning more about Rina.
I want to help my master.
The First Law.
Would you please keep this from Rina?
The café's rule?
I don't want to hurt anyone.
Selfish, aren't you?
Pathetic person.
It's probably impossible for everyone to be happy.
Thank you.
We should
get out of here
Well then, excuse us.
I guess there are all sorts.
Of humans?
Androids too.
Sorry I hit you.
Your eyes were right.
I should've taken a good look myself.
Masaki.
Yeah?
So you've seen the light?
I'm not an junior high school kid!
But, Rina is...
No, it's the other way around, isn't it?
Wait a sec.
What did Rina say?
So you come here for Koji... for your, I mean, your master's protection?
No.
She never once said her master was Koji.
Master
She didn't.
Outside of the café, they're unrelated?
Master
But they both say the other is human.
Human
There's a contradiction here.
Thanks for waiting.
They might not know about each other.
Okay! That's it for the hints.
Human
They're the same.
Explain yourself.
Partners not knowing what the other is...
It's the same for androids.
The two of them are interested in each other...
...for different reasons.
They're each hiding things from the other.
So what?
It's like a normal romance.
That's something good, isn't it?
But you shouldn't interfere too much.
Love between androids...
Pseudo-love, you mean?
So, the woman in the photo from the other day...
Who was she?
Um...
Androids in a love triangle.
It's a bit hard to explain.
A difficult-to-explain woman?
Androids tangled in blind love.
Don't make weird comments!
You'll tell me about it properly someday, won't you?
Uh... really?
Welcome home, master.
Nao-chan and Mom have gone out for dinner.
Sammy, take care of the rest.
What's that in your hair?
Does it displease you?
The likelihood of vagrant androids having corrupted thought logic is dangerously high. Please report all discoveries immediately.
Vagrant Robot Reporting Hotline
This is a request from the Ethics Committee.
At the moment, the Ethics Committee
is undertaking independent recovery of vagrant robots
that have been removed from the supervision of their masters...
What is this drawing of?
You don't recognize yourself?
Is this... me?
Yes!
It's a drawing of you, —
It sure is quiet, isn't it?
You mean, there aren't any customers.
Well...
Huh?
Did they leave?
This really is a strange café in many ways, isn't it?
U-Um, Nagi-san, how come you work here?
"Nagi" is fine.
Because I like it.
And the people who come here.
So it's lonely on days like today when I can't see the people I like.
Uh, what about us?
Huh? What?
Here. A refill.
I'll go get the beans.
Wait a sec.
Make yourselves at home.
It really is quiet, isn't it?
It's an LUH model.
A houseroid from when we were in elementary school.
They're still around...
I've never seen one before.
It wasn't very popular.
Lots of complaints because it was hard to use.
It's shaking all over the place.
Do you have some business here?
We're just customers.
Do you know what a customer is?
I am also a customer.
Hey!
I'm Masaki. This guy's Rikuo.
So, who are you?
Wh-What are you doing?
Humans usually introduce themselves.
Introducing myself means telling you my name, does it not?
This thing is pretending to be human.
It's obeying the rule.
Yes! It's a drawing of you, —
My name is —
Why are you covering your ears?
If I do not tell you my name, I cannot finish my introduction.
In other words, I am unable to prove that I am human.
My name is —
All right! Don't force yourself.
To do what?
To introduce yourself!
Why is that? Just now, Masaki-sama said:
Humans usually introduce themselves.
That is what you said.
Masaki!
This one can't deal with ambiguous interactions.
What're we gonna do?
Anyhow, if we don't let it introduce itself—
That sound?!
We'll just have to listen to it.
We're sorry!
Go ahead and say it!
Like I said, I am —
I-It's a nice name, isn't it?
I think so, too.
It is a precious name.
That's nice.
Where might be the restroom?
It's been left alone for so long that it's falling apart.
I'm amazed the manufacturer hasn't collected it.
Again, talking about stuff like that.
This one is definitely—
Rikuo-kun.
He's a customer.
You should know by now.
Everyone who comes here gets the same treatment.
Excuse me.
Welcome.
What would you like to order?
Something seems wrong.
Maybe it can't make a decision.
Probably its first time.
Ouch!
Order! One more cup of this!
I will order the same as Rikuo-sama.
Yep, two Evlends!
Gonna drink the coffee?
Three cups might be too much.
No, I mean the robot.
That mouth is just a speaker.
What if it tries to imitate a human by drinking?
If it does that...
Hey, wait a sec!
Three Laws of Robotics
Third Law
A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection
does not conflict with the First or Second Law.
The Third Law! Robots can't commit suicide.
It must know what'll happen if it drinks.
That's right!
There's no way it would drink... right?
Is something wrong?
Coffee is...
dangerous!
Wh-What are you doing?!
What do you mean?
Here are your Evlends!
Why?!
So this customer can drink it, obviously.
Don't ask silly questions.
Hey, wait a sec!
Turn it off!
I've never done that before!
Order it!
It should listen if you order it!
Ah, right!
Drop the cup! That's an order!
Why?
"Why?"
That lady said:
So this customer can drink it, obviously.
Don't ask silly questions.
That is what she said.
I am a customer.
Question!
What might that be?
Uh...
H-How old are you?
My age?
I will be eight this year.
Huh?
Probably means it was made eight years ago.
You think I am big for an eight-year-old human, do you not?
No, that's not—
No, Masaki-sama, it was written all over your face.
Why worry about that little detail?
But I am eight years old...
Eight years...
Eight...
Hey!
Its logic and the rule are in conflict!
Eight...
It can't answer!
What do we do?
There are lots of different kinds of eight year olds!
Are you saying that there are eight-year-old humans the same size as me?
Right!
That is not in my data.
Please explain in detail.
It's... it's someone who comes here a lot!
Someone who comes here, and is eight years old, right?
What is their name?
Ch-Chie-chan!
She's already eight years old... not quite, huh?
8 Years
Not quite eight years
Yeah, yeah! She's big?
Her voice, at least...
Thank you for believing me.
What is your job?
I assisted with childcare.
Childcare, huh?
Yes.
The parents and one son...
Hey! Talk to it!
Huh?
It's hard by myself.
I am a customer.
Thank you for the drink.
A liquid tank.
After all that trouble...
I guess the danger has passed.
Excuse me, where is Nagi-san?
I fell asleep while watching her take her afternoon nap.
Something weird is sitting here!
You shouldn't say stuff like that, Chie-chan.
Let's go back, okay?
I'm a cat!
Um...
Excuse me.
Chie-chan!
Chie-chan is the one who is not quite eight years old?
What?
This person... is Chie-chan!
What? What are you saying?
Who is this?
I'm a cat!
She's a cat!
No... That's just what she likes to—
Can't we just call her a cat?!
She says it herself, so let's leave it at that!
Okay!
I-am-a-cat!
All right! I will escort you to the door!
Good-bye!
Right now, my information is very—
Hey! Are you okay—
Something weird came off.
Ah, is there any way I can help—
I'm begging you, please just go.
What do you think? Can you fix it?
This is already—
Thank you, Rikuo-kun.
But...
Since we have the chance, let's have a nice chat.
So you've always worked at that house?
Yes.
That was my workplace.
I was employed to take care of the son,
but he has already grown to the point where he no longer needs me.
Did you like that job?
Yes.
The son bestowed a name upon me,
and even now, I remember it well.
It is a precious name.
That child's name! What was his name?
The son...
was called —
What about the family's name?
Address? Contact information?
You were...
Like I thought...
I am grateful that you asked my name.
Everyone who comes here is treated the same.
You are the one who invited me here, right?
Do not forget... my name.
Yes! It's a drawing of you, Katoran!
Is it broken?
It was abandoned illegally.
Huh?
If you buy a new one, you have the manufacturer collect the old one, right?
At that time—
The collection fee...
They deleted their personal information because they didn't want to pay it.
It wanted to be remembered by someone, you see?
Its own name...
Because of that, it kept running from the Ethics Committee.
It probably didn't know.
It probably didn't even know its own name.
That was probably erased too.
That's just like a robot, isn't it?
It lost its name ages ago and didn't even realize it.
Those memories were in its heart the whole time.
The precious memories of when it received its name.
Heart?
What do you mean, "Heart"?
Masaki!
You said it often enough yourself!
"They can't understand music because they have no heart."
Stop feeling sorry for that thing!
Stop it already!
What?
It's not... normal.
Right?
You too?
Vagrant Robot Report Form
So they're disposing of vagrant robots, too.
The Ethics Committee, I mean.
I have nothing to do with it.
She really is ignoring us, huh?
Isn't that normal?
Sammy's like that at home, too.
Why is it different only at that café?
Feelings is something they lack.
Is this... me?
Yes! It's a drawing of you, Katoran!
In a Time of Tenderness
Next, the front page of the Bankei newspaper.
Android job types expand!
It's big news!
Where's Sammy?
Left ages ago after making that.
Maintenance, huh?
It's so annoying - once every month.
Where does it go? An appliance shop?
I dunno. Probably dad's place?
I'm sleepy. I don't feel like eating.
Android job types expand.
Androids used as school teachers?
Birth of android artists?
The piano.
What?
If you're gonna play at night, turn off the sound!
Even I couldn't sleep.
So it wasn't a dream.
Mom was heartbroken.
Gone to teach voice training.
Sammy, take care of breakfast.
— Mom
Says she can't let you help with the lessons.
Even if I get good, what's the use?
Hayama Junior Piano Competition
Robot gives guest performance.
Grand Prix—Rikuo Kikuhara (14 years old)
It doesn't have any special abilities?
An android with special abilities?
I found this on my dad's PC.
Let's see...
It's an android.
Designed to be a human's parent.
I've never heard of—
They aren't actually on the market.
They want to use them in the near future.
Read this part.
...Operational tests conducted in secret...
Sounds familiar, doesn't it?
That doesn't mean he's definitely—
Good grief. Robots are pushing their way into everything.
After art, it's love, eh?
Masaki!
Would you eat a tomato created by machines?
Welcome!
You're alone today?
It's not like we're always together.
Sure you are!
She's alone, too?
Ah, yeah.
Shimei-san's got something to take care of.
So you provide daycare too.
Chie-chan is a customer!
Right?
Meow...
What's he doing that he had to leave Chie-chan alone?
I'm a cat!
Don't say stuff like that.
Sure, sure.
Hopefully your dad will be back soon.
He's not my dad!
Who is he, then?
He's called my... fos... ter... par... ent!
I'm back, Chie-chan!
I'm a cat.
Ah, Rikuo-kun!
Huh? Where's Masaki-kun?
Like I said, we're not always together.
Sure you are!
You seem kind of out of it.
Out of it, meow.
I am not!
Chie-chan, let's read a book!
I don't feel like it...
You know which book Uncle Shimei likes?
How about I show you?
Meow!
She's good with kids, isn't she?
Because she's an adult.
Unlike me.
What does Shimei-san do for a living?
I don't know either, other than doting on Chie-chan.
He could have taken her with him.
It's probably hard on Shimei-san.
Somehow I understand that...
given how many times I've taken care of her.
Many times?
Yeah.
Every month.
Cats study too!
Are you all right?
Just a bit low on sleep.
That's not what I meant.
You seem to be in a bad mood.
I'm just an unpleasant person anyways!
What's that supposed to mean?
They say there's nothing in your heart when you've just been born.
It's empty.
Cats too?
Right. But, see, you talk with lots of people,
and feel and see lots of things,
and gradually your heart fills up.
Cats too?
Right, but you're still a child.
You're going to experience a lot more emotions.
Meow.
Not just Chie-chan's.
Shimei-san, us, and also -
Rikuo-san?
The cat understands!
Really?!
Meow!
Chie-chan beat me to it...
Are you lonely when Shimei-san isn't around?
Do you like Shimei-san?
Meow...
Shimei-san goes off somewhere on his own.
I wonder where he goes, even though it makes you lonely.
Rikuo-kun!
She's just a child, you know!
Ah, sorry.
Um... Bathroom...
Now it's Chie-chan's turn!
Rikuo-kun, excuse us a sec.
Ah, yeah.
I can do it by myself.
That's my Chie-chan!
It's been quite a while since Shimei first brought her to this café.
According to that elderly gentleman, this is her favorite place.
I didn't mean to upset her.
However, something's bothering—
It can't be helped.
All human beings hurt those around them sometimes.
What are you getting at?
I guess that got you angry.
Are you saying I'm an unpleasant person because I'm human?
You bring up an interesting point.
Do you think if you were a robot you'd never hurt anyone?
What is it that hurts others?
It's not such an easy thing to figure out.
What were your thoughts at that time?
How can you avoid hurting others?
What do you need to understand?
It's easy enough to say it,
but quite another thing to put into action.
Rikuo-san!
You saved me!
Is that so?
This sucks.
So you're going forward with Administration of Justice?
I hear there aren't many lawyers specializing in Robotics Law yet.
But it's still tough to get into that school.
What about you?
This, after all, huh?
I'm quitting.
Why?
Is this about what happened the other day?
Yeah.
It's nothing to worry about.
I'm sure it plays accurately,
but it just stole a bit of the limelight.
It was really... good.
I was moved... I think.
By this?
Huh?
It's lousy, eh?
It is!
I'm sorry.
I lied when I said I could play.
But you made it to the end, didn't you?
Really, I just picked it up by watching someone.
I've just heard it so many times, that's all.
Chie-chan says she wants to hear more!
Play some more!
Play! Play!
Meow!
Chie-chan, which part did you like best?
I'm a cat!
Um... when it was all broken up!
Broken up?
Broken up.
It was broken up.
Look at that!
Isn't that amazing?
Hey, Rikuo-kun—
Thanks for this.
That's not what you were playing before!
Ma-
Rikuo-san.
Um... I...
The song you used to play...
I... like it...
And then Chie-chan said she wanted to hear it.
But I've never actually played it.
But she looked like she was enjoying it, so I...
I'm sorry to have been so selfish.
I didn't want to play in front of you.
Before I knew it, I'd stopped playing.
I would hate it if even you got good at the piano.
Rikuo-san.
But...
To hell with all that!
Meow! Meow! Meow!
I want to hear more!
Sammy-chan might play for you!
Meow!
I'm so happy.
She hasn't been that happy for a long time.
It was no big deal...
And as for me...
I left her on her own again.
You can't take her with you?
I don't want to show her yet.
Shimei-san, are you perhaps—
She needs me,
so I devote myself to her.
She is everything to me.
My only wish is to make her happy.
Like your performance...
That's why I was so happy.
These feelings are genuine.
Your performance moved me, I swear.
Should you be saying that?
Just don't tell Nagi-san.
Have you seen Sammy-chan?
Now that you mention it, I think she left when I came in.
So she left...
For your hard work.
About Sammy...
What about her?
I was just thinking that she's making a lot of friends.
I'm not angry or anything!
You were really great.
This café...
You know, I kind of like it...
Thank you.
Rikuo-kun!
That's right.
I'll explain it at the next meeting.
I'm home.
Anyway, take a look at the records.
Regardless of what those at the top say,
this is the best way to investigate them all.
Where's Dad?
He went to the Family Court.
He is expected home shortly.
There's no way mom did anything wrong.
That is true.
However, you mustn't blame just your father,
since neither of them is completely in the wrong.
But...
I have a favor to ask of you.
Sure.
Please keep this conversation a secret from your father.
Why?
Because it would hurt your father.
You wouldn't want that, would you?
So, that is the favor I'm asking of you.
Sure!
Masakazu, there's a problem.
I think it broke.
Good morning, Tex.
Tex...
Hey, Tex!
Tex!
Next, the report from the preliminary investigation.
This shows the places that seem to be inciting excessive human-robot interactions.
Too many.
There are 1,408 places.
We gathered all possible information and codified all of it.
Groundless rumors and urban legends included.
We need to narrow it down.
Time of Eve
Unfortunately, the list is not limited to places that clearly violate robotic law.
It's a grey zone.
And the fact that there are so many of these places
shows the limitations to robot law as it stands now.
However, these places should be erased.
We'll do an initial investigation of all the places,
and then pick targets for full investigation.
After that, hand them over to the media.
But it's impossible given the sheer number!
That's true if you think in terms of manpower.
For the first time, we will use androids for the initial investigations.
We have already secured the necessary units, and are currently preparing them.
What happened to your allergy to robots?
Fight poison with poison.
I suggest you think of it like that.
Continue.
Yes, sir.
We'll only fully investigate the places substantiated by the initial android investigations.
At the same time, we will record the presence of all humans and androids and carry out follow-up investigations.
We'll immediately report suspects to committee members who are in the police force and urge them to make arrests.
What's happening with the Android Promotion Committee?
There's a report that someone has discovered the preliminary investigation.
Their relationship with the APC is unclear.
Furthermore, their lobbying appears to have died down at this time.
And don't forget,
that some parties will try using this investigation to trip us up.
We will order the android investigators
to keep their ties with our committee absolutely secret.
Memories of that injury incident are fading.
We must not make the same mistake again.
Go on, please.
Media strategy division.
Concerning CIO Masaki's TV appearance—
My wife records every one of them.
Drives me nuts!
I'd like to emphasize
that our Ethics Committee is raising the alarm
about robots infiltrating into daily life, that's all.
Whoa! What a lady killer!
How so?
Hey, you changed the channel.
Thanks for letting me stop by!
Children especially treat robots as if they are human, no matter how primitive they are.
And that impedes the relationships that we're supposed to have between humans.
One Evlend!
Human dignity is being violated.
Sure.
The issue I'm raising here is...
Hey, why doesn't Masaki-kun come anymore?
To tell the truth, a lot has happened.
Like what?!
Well, the biggest reason is...
This guy is on TV a lot these days, huh?
Yeah.
Like the old days...
What do you mean?
The Robot Ethics Committee has been around since androids started being used in households.
More than ten years ago.
I've heard that it started out as a radical anti-robot organization.
I had no idea.
Because they've been quiet for the last few years.
What do you mean?
In the past, their extremism led to an injury.
The Tokisaka Incident, right?
I've heard of it.
Well, it's also been called an accident,
but at any rate, they were severely censured, and the chairman resigned.
Since then, they've been quiet, at least until recently.
You've lost me.
Does that have anything to do with Masaki-kun?
...that is our stance.
Thank you very much, Masaki-sama.
Today's guest on Zoom-in Scramble has been Masaki Atsuro-sama of the Ethics Committee's Public Relations Office.
Masaki...
That's right... his family circumstances...
I invited him today—
So Masaki is his last name.
You're hung up on that?
Not that!
So, how's it going?
There's this café called Time of Eve.
Rikuo's a big fan.
Well, I go there too, so who am I to talk.
Humans and androids talk to each other normally.
It's totally absurd, isn't it?
Isn't it?
Say something.
I'm coming in.
Who are you talking to?
My cell phone.
I hung up already.
You had it make coffee?
Uh, yeah.
You've been home a lot lately.
Did something happen?
Tell me everything.
There's nothing to tell.
I see.
Don't trust robots with your food or drink too much.
THX, tonight we'll write up the minutes from today's meeting.
The data is in my terminal.
Tell Masaki-kun he's welcome anytime.
Sure, I'll tell him.
But don't get your hopes up.
See you.
Bye bye!
Come again!
Um, he's gone...
You know, I don't think Rikuo-kun minds anymore.
That's the impression I get.
Nagi-san, you don't understand Rikuo.
I've known him longer.
I'm sure he doesn't want to see me here yet.
Really?
Hey, who cares about Rikuo-kun?
Of course we care about him!
Please don't talk like that!
Is that so?
Don't go telling Rikuo-kun strange things.
Bye bye!
Masaki-kun's not going to report this place, is he...?
Meow.
If that happens, this café will just have to close.
But it's such a wonderful place.
Sammy-chan,
do you remember how you first came here?
I thought you invited me.
I can't bring anyone here.
You probably learned about Time of Eve
from someone who'd been here.
And Sammy-chan, you brought Rikuo-kun and Masaki-kun.
So if Masaki-kun brings someone from the Ethics Committee, there's nothing you can do about it.
That's where those connections end.
And the end of this café.
Are you okay with that, Nagi-san?
In this café, everyone's hearts come together as one.
I just want to see it through.
How big can this circle grow?
Um, Master—
Wh-What?
Do you want Masaki-sama to come again?
To the Time of Eve.
Yes, I'd like him to come again.
Me too. Very much.
Okay, I'll bring him tomorrow for sure!
Masaki!
Today—
I'm not going.
She said she wants you to come again.
Don't just say things.
It's true!
Who?
Um, Nagi-san, and—
Sammy said so, too!
That guy said he wants you to come as well.
She wants me to come?
So what?
It's a houseroid!
Yeah.
That's right.
You've... changed.
Masaki!
Hey! What's going on?
You're just like I was, back then.
You'll feel love, only to be betrayed later.
It'd be better if that café didn't exist.
That's it.
It'd be better if it didn't exist.
Dad! I want to talk to you about something.
The THX is gone.
Masakazu, did you give it an order?
No.
It just went off on its own.
It's completely broken.
Gotta find it right away, and get rid of it.
Get rid of it?
Of course!
It's dealt with a lot of Ethics Committee material.
Gotta take care of it, before it becomes a major problem!
Masaki, I'm at the Time of Eve right now!
Can you help me?
What's that sound?
An ancient robot—
— an elderly customer is here.
It says to close the café!
I said, what is that sound?
The screen...
Anyway, it won't stop, no matter what we say!
And this THX model won't talk at all.
Hey! What did you just say?
This café is a gray zone, right?
Can't you come here and do something with those robot laws of yours?
That was fast!
Close thi
establishment immediately.
Tex, stop it.
T-Tex?
What are you doing here?
Oh, so that's what this is about?
You brought our robot here to show me some cheap play, huh?
I don't know how you brought it here,
but hey, you got Rikuo's robot to come here.
You can do all kinds of things at this mysterious café, after all.
I-It's not like Nagi-chan brought—
Aki-chan.
So you'd go that far to get me to come here.
I'll tell you my story.
Long ago, it raised me.
It was my best friend.
Then one day, it suddenly stopped talking.
I was a kid, and I felt hurt and betrayed by this thing I thought was family.
That's all.
No big deal.
There must be a reason why it doesn't talk.
I agree.
It doesn't look like it's that broken.
I know.
I was four or five years old, but I could guess what was going on.
My dad ordered it...
not to talk, no matter what.
He tried to drive us apart.
It's just the sort of thing he'd do.
Orders from parents get priority.
Masaki-kun, you're very perceptive.
What's perceptive?
I didn't know that when I was a kid!
I kept trying to talk with it.
I begged for forgiveness, in tears!
If commanded, it can ignore a crying, wailing child.
For years.
In the end...
they can't understand people's hearts!
...use androids for the initial investigations.
There's this café called the Time of Eve.
I go there too, so who am I to talk.
...record the presence of all humans and androids...
...urge arrests.
...places should be erased.
I am going to b-break th-this café's rule.
You are in violation of Robotics Law 9, Article 3.
According to data in my possession, you are an android.
If an android turns off its ring while activated, it is in violation of robotics law.
What's going on?
Why is Tex speaking?
What about Dad's command?
A command...
It's breaking a command.
It's breaking the Second Law.
Only the First Law can override the Second Law.
The First Law means... danger?
Someone is—
A human is—
A human here is in danger?
No, I'm the only one Tex knows is human.
I'm in danger?
So Tex is speaking...
to protect me?
Thus, it is necessary to take legal action against your owner.
I require information on your owner.
We will order the android investigators to keep their ties with our committee absolutely secret.
Masaki-san!
Masaki!
Masaki-kun!
I'm not letting go!
I'm not letting go until you talk to me!
Tell me!
What were you thinking?
For all those years.
All that time.
Watching me, all those years.
You were right there with me.
Tex, help me!
Speak to me!
I couldn't speak to you.
I always wanted to be at your side.
I...
always...
Masakazu-kun...
I guess it wanted to protect you.
I know that.
It won't speak once the danger has passed.
It's still bound by dad's command.
You wanted me to understand, too, huh?
But, after all, I can't accept this.
It might be impossible now,
but I'm sure someday it will be able to talk.
Don't just say things.
You're wrong.
It's not like I don't have a reason.
I can't express it well...
but I've seen so many things here.
There's a lot of problems.
Each time it's distressing.
But I feel that this is the right path.
It's the same for you, Masaki.
So, I'm sure...
You may be right.
I'll tell dad I took you out of the house.
I...
always...
Masakazu-kun...
Let's go home.
How did it get in?
I held it up.
I lifted it up.
You really are demanding a lot!
Someday I'll get you to say thanks for this.
I love everyone.
I'm so happy we can all be here.
They're going home together!
Hush!
Should I have helped them?
No, it's enough that you watched over them.
It might have turned into another dangerous incident.
I'm sure Shiotsuki understands that much.
But is this really related to Shiotsuki?
That café's rule...
Indeed, rule #1138.
1138.
"Our country's robot force will continue to act upon prioritized orders."
That would make sense.
Code: LIFE's suppressed reformation isn't working.
This is all to prepare for that time.
Time of Eve's rule
In this café,
there will be no discrimination
between humans and robots.
Customers, please cooperate.
Obey the rule and have a fun time...
To think that someone other than Shiotsuki could...
But—
One more thing.
Android control taken to new extremes
An article about the Tokisaka Incident from back then?
No, this is...
It's the real article, before the contents were replaced prior to publication.
A girl, five years old at the time.
If by chance she is still alive...
Time of Eve
Continued Investigation
Investigation Unnecessary
On hold
I forgot your Evlend today.
I thought something was missing.
How did Tex get to the café?
You don't know?
You do?
And I thought you were a regular here.
Rikuo-kun, you've got a long way to go.
S-Still a long way?
Someone new?
I'm going to say hello.
This is the story of my days at the Time of Eve.
Welcome!
Take a seat!
I'll come and take your order.
Many different things happened here after this...
You might not be here for long, but enjoy yourself!
...but that's another story.
kouen no bench de waratteita
We were laughing on a park bench
natsu no asa, sougen ga midori ni kagayaiteta
The summer morning shone upon the green grasslands
hontou wa mienai kimi no hitomi donna iro
I really can't see your eyes; what color are they?
kimi ga miteru sora wo mitsuketakute
I want to find the sky you're watching
I have a dream
sasayaka sugite totemo
It's very meager
kimi ni iesou ni wa nai
I can't seem to tell you what it is
keredo asa ga kuru me wo kosuri
However, the morning comes and I rub my eyes
hitogomi wo aruiteku
I'll walk through the crowds
kurikaesu hibi no naka
Within these repeating days
chiisana yume wo sagashi tsudzukeru
Continuing to search for my little dream
toki wa yuku bokutachi wa surechigai mata deau
Time goes by; we pass by each other and meet again
kogoeteta fuyu no hi wo kamishimete
I dwell on a frozen winter day
asa ga kuru kaze ga fuku
The morning comes and the wind blows
hitogomi wo aruiteku
I'll walk through the crowds
kimi no tame boku no tame
For you and for me
sekai wa yume wo tsumugi tsudzukeru
The world keeps on spinning its dream
I'm back.
Looks like it's still fine.
You worked hard.
Though it doesn't smell like salt anymore,
I still like the café as it is.
It's in the city, so lots of people gather there.
Is everyone doing fine?
Yes.
You look sad.
She...
Ever since she was broken by Ashimori,
she's been feeling insecure.
They—
Will they find happiness?
No matter how many times I try...
How many times has it been now?
The third time...
Or fourth time...
They—
Will they be able to laugh?
I...
Your children are laughing—
Alongside humans.
I feel insecure.
It's unbearable.
It's all right.
Someday, definitely, it will extend beyond the café.
Something happened today to make me think that.
Won't you tell me about it?
The main character is a certain boy.
So today's story is...