Kiba!
Wait up, damn it!
You're going too fast!
Let's rest for a while.
We don't have time.
Think it through,
damn it!
We've got a girl
and a kid with us!
We can hear you, Hige.
Don't worry about me,
I can keep up.
Me, too...
He's the one who wants
to rest, that's all.
I do not!
I just...
But there's some sense
in what Hige's saying.
At this rate, none
of us will make it.
Let's wait over there for
the snowstorm to die down.
I guess that settles it. Can you
hang in there a little longer?
You should worry
about yourself.
Yes, ma'am,
you're right.
Let's go.
It'll be dawn soon.
Let's rest here until then.
Let's do that, Kiba.
The snowstorm will let up by then.
It already is.
Let's go.
It'll be fine.
We won't be fine!
I'm going anyway.
I can handle it.
Yeah, let's go.
Forget it! I'm staying here
until morning.
I understand.
Kiba!
Let him go!
But...
All he has eyes for
right now is Cheza.
Whether we're with him or not
doesn't make any difference.
We'll go after him later. For now,
clear your head and rest up.
Are you really
sure about this?
That guy obsesses
too much.
So, I take it you didn't
like that scarf.
Too bad, I thought it would
look good on you.
Okay, maybe not.
Lunkhead.
Cheza is...
She's a girl that was created from
Lunar Flowers using alchemy.
And the man who created
Cheza was Darcia the First.
Lord Orkham stole her
and had us study her.
To awaken her and open
the door to Paradise.
Paradise...
It's a world where
wolves reign.
And Lunar Flowers are there to guide
the world's remaining wolves to Paradise.
Did you know all this
from the very beginning?
Who did you learn
it from, then?!
Wait a minute! You mean at the castle
we're headed to, there's...
A world of wolves, huh?
If a place like that is Paradise, I'll head straight
on down to Hell if it's all the same to you.
You were awake?
It's too cold
to stay drunk.
The Book of the Moon
isn't just some story.
Maybe so.
But even if you're right,
what can we humans do?
I'll never forgive wolves.
Even if they are the ones
who rule this world,
I'm gonna exterminate
every last one of 'em.
Lord Darcia. Inside
the keep, there is...
A wolf?
Yes.
Now that I have lost you, my beloved,
Paradise holds no meaning for me.
And yet...
This wolf's eye throbs.
Why?
What is this feeling that
threatens to overwhelm me...
My beloved Hamona...
Tell me.
What should l...
He is here.
This is Darcia's keep, huh?
This looks like the sort of place
that would be haunted.
By what?
The ghosts of
cursed Nobles.
Come on, don't talk about
stuff like that!
Still, are you sure that
girl is really here?
It's faint, but I smell
a Lunar Flower.
Looks like he already
has visitors.
Blue!
It's Pops!
Hey, what's gotten
into you?!
Let's go!
Who are the Nobles,
anyway?
Most of the literature
dealing with them...
...was lost with the decline
of civilization.
But we do know
a few things.
They say that long before the
world became as it is now,
they extolled the virtues
of civilization,
using their fantastic alchemy
to blaze a path to the stars,
and open doors into
space and time.
But all that vanished
in an instant.
No one knows what
happened then.
But many people
disappeared,
and the inner workings of alchemy came
to be a secret known only to the Nobles...
...that was not to be passed
on to the people.
That was more than
two hundred years ago.
And now this world
is quietly passing away.
Along with the
red moon.
They are here.
Cheza!
Kiba!
Why are you in
such a rush?
He's here.
Pops is here...
Do you really want to
see this "Pops" guy?
No. It would be better
if I didn't.
Maybe he's looking
for you, Blue.
And what if he is?
Are you gonna go back
to being a dog?
Hey, lay off!
You don't know what
it feels like, Tsume!
I guess I don't.
I've never been kept as a pet
by humans like you two.
Now, now, first things first.
Let's find Kiba and Cheza.
The flower scent is coming
from this way.
Wolf worship, huh?
It's not a simple
animal cult.
I think this world has split into
a world that we humans can see...
...and a world that we lost
sight of at some point.
I'm certain that the animals
are aware of that.
Including wolves, huh?
What brought that on?
I was born
allergic to dogs.
I see. They must be
off that way, then.
Allergies can
come in handy.
Glad I could help.
Kiba!
Cheza!
Have you come
for revenge, wolf?
Don't hurt Cheza.
Cheza is merely an embodiment of
Lunar Flowers that we created.
Why do you want
Cheza so badly?
I don't know who
you Nobles are.
And I don't care what
you people are.
Cheza is going to tell us
the way to Paradise.
Wolf... It all began
with your kind.
What is it?
Hey!
You and your kind stole
everything from me.
And in return, you gave me a curse.
And suffering. And grief.
And this eye became
just like yours.
All this was the price I paid
for being cursed by Paradise.
And now... all I am surrounded
by is despair.
Don't! What is it
that you want?!
Have you found it?
Have you found Paradise?
We will.
No matter what!
What is it that you expect
to find in Paradise?
A future.
A future?
Not hope. Not despair.
Just a future.
Nothing more.
I no longer have
any need...
...for a future.
You damn wolf!
No, don't!
Blue...
Kiba!
Lord Darcia!
Cheza!
Kiba!
CHEZA!
Blue!
Cheza!
We need to hurry!
Why?
Why, Blue...?
Quent!
Blue!
Jaguara!
That way!
Did that wolf
just talk...?!
Kiba!
Don't go after them!
The Fallen Keep
Next Time
A human life is an
ephemeral thing.
It is a good idea to look
to the past from time to time.
But perhaps my life is a trifle too long
to look back and dwell upon.
And so,
I bid you farewell.
Grey Wolf
And so,
I bid you farewell.
Grey Wolf